I think most of us do the first date
我觉得我们大多数人第一次约会都做得
completely wrong. We set ourselves up to
一塌糊涂。 我们自取灭亡
fail. And the reason why is because
。 原因很简单，因为
it's so true. I [laughter] can't believe
它说得太对了。 我（笑）简直不敢相信
how true this is.
这是真的。
Paul Brunson, the world's most
保罗·布伦森，世界上最
influential matchmaker. [music]
有影响力的媒人。  [音乐]
He's got a hit show on Oprah's network.
他在奥普拉的电视网主持一档热门节目。
UK.
英国。
This you may never have heard before. My
你可能从未听说过这件事。 我的
expertise is relationship science. And
专长是关系科学。
the beauty of science is that [music] if
科学的美妙之处在于（音乐），如果
you can change the formula, you change
你能改变公式，就能改变
the result. So if you are someone who is
结果。 所以，如果你正处于
in a relationship and you're unsure how
恋爱关系中，却不知道如何
to communicate, there's certain things
沟通，那么
that you could change.
你可以改变一些事情。
Tell me what those are.
告诉我那些是什么。
It seems so simple, but it literally
这看起来很简单，但它确实
changed my marriage. So we're terrible
改变了我的婚姻。 所以，我们在
rational decision around our love life.
爱情生活中做出任何理性决定方面都很糟糕。
And if you can't have emotional
如果你无法建立情感上的
intimacy, you just simply can't have a
亲密关系，你就根本无法建立一段
relationship. You have acquaintances,
关系。 你有熟人，
you have situationships, but you [music]
你有暧昧关系，但你（音乐）
don't have relationships.
没有真正的关系。
Let's talk about sex. Can you be
我们来谈谈性吧。 你可能会被
physically attracted to somebody but
某人的外表吸引，但却
then not have sexual attraction? There
没有性吸引力吗？
are different languages, sexual
语言有很多种，性方面的
languages. You have to understand how
语言也有很多种。 你必须了解
your [music] partner, the language that
你的（音乐）伴侣，了解
they speak sex in. Men, we need to know
他们用什么语言谈论性。男人们，我们需要知道
this. 70 to 80% of women [music] need.
这一点。  70%到80%的女性[音乐]需要。   在
Before this episode begins, I just want
本期节目开始之前，我想
to say a huge thank you to all of our
对所有
new subscribers. 74% of you that watch
新订阅者表示衷心的感谢。 观看本频道的观众中，74%
this channel didn't subscribe before and
之前没有订阅过，
we're now down to about 71%. So that
现在这个比例下降到了 71% 左右。 这
helps us in a number of ways that are
在很多方面对我们都有帮助，这些方面
quite hard to explain, but simply the
很难解释，但简单来说，
bigger the channel gets, the bigger the
频道越大，
guests get. So, if you haven't yet
嘉宾的影响力也就越大。 所以，如果你还没有
subscribed to the Diary of a SEO, if I
订阅《SEO日记》，如果你
could have any favors from you, if
能帮我个忙，如果
you've ever watched this show and
你看过这个节目并且
enjoyed it, it's just to please hit the
喜欢它，那就请点击
subscribe button. Without further ado,
订阅按钮。 废话不多说，
I'm Steven Bartlett and this is the
我是史蒂文·巴特利特，这里是
Diary of a CEO. I hope nobody's
CEO日记。 我希望没人
listening, but if you are, then please
听到，但如果你听到了，请你把
keep this to yourself. [music]
这些话藏在心里。  [音乐]
[singing]
[歌唱]
[music]
[音乐]
Give me your context. What do I need to
请告诉我你的情况。 我需要
know about you from your earliest years
了解你生命
from those first what 15 16 years of
最初15、16年里的哪些经历，才能让
your life that would give me the context
我了解你，从而
I need to understand the person you are
理解你
today?
今天的为人？
So I was born in Jamaica, Queens.
我出生在皇后区的牙买加。
Oh wow.
哇哦。
You know and our claim to fame is uh is
你知道，我们引以为豪的是，呃，我
is Curtis Jackson 50 Cent, right? Uh
是 Curtis Jackson，也就是 50 Cent，对吧？ 呃，
being shot nine times in our
在我们社区被枪击了九次
neighborhood. That's our claim to fame.
。 这就是我们引以为傲的地方。
But everyone was like, "Okay, I get it.
但大家都说：“好吧，我明白了。
That's that's where it was." Um so grew
原来是在那里。” 嗯，我在
up there. It was a heavy Caribbean,
那里长大。 这是一个以加勒比海地区、
Jamaican uh first and second generation
牙买加裔为主的社区，第一代和第二代移民都居住于此
neighborhood, but my father was who was
，但我父亲是
the first in his family to go to
他家族中第一个上
college. He focused in uh computer
大学的人。 他主攻计算机
science.
科学。
Oh wow.
哇哦。   是的
Yeah. And so he, you know, hustled and
。 所以，你知道，他努力奋斗，
my mother hustled and was they we were
我母亲也努力奋斗，我们终于
able to buy a home in Long Island and
在长岛买了一栋房子，就像
that was the like you've made it. You've
你成功了一样。 你已经
moved out the city and you've moved to
搬出了市区，搬到了
to Long Island. We were the first black
长岛。 我们是第一个
family to live in this neighborhood. The
居住在这个社区的黑人家庭。 第
first, and I'm talking about a 100
一个，我指的是100套
homes.
住宅。
We were the first black family. Because
我们是第一个黑人家庭。 正因
of that, when I moved to that
如此，当我搬到那个
neighborhood, I was the underdog. I was
社区时，我成了弱势群体。 我是个
the outsider. And I was treated as such.
局外人。 而我也确实受到了这样的对待。
I remember being on the bus and just
我记得当时我在公交车上，然后就被撞到了
glass. Um, punched, kicked, you know?
玻璃上。 嗯，挨打、踢踹，你知道吗？
It's one of these where I mean for no
这是那种毫无理由，仅仅因为
color of my skin. Um so that was that
我的肤色而遭受歧视的情况。 嗯，这就是我的
was growing up.
成长经历。
And how is that manifested in your adult
那么，这在你的成年生活中是如何体现的呢
life?
？
I'm a fighter. You know I think that's
我是一个斗士。 你知道吗，我觉得这才是
really what I you know it's interesting.
真正有趣的地方。
I even I notice when I walk into a room
甚至我自己也注意到，当我走进一个房间时，
I seek out the underdog and I try to
我会寻找那些弱势群体，并努力
champion them. So if I walk into a room,
支持他们。 所以如果我走进一个房间，
I'll look for the person who's hugging
我会寻找
the wall, the person who's in the corner
靠墙站着的人，或者独自待在角落里的人
by themselves, and I will intentionally
，然后我会故意
walk over to them, you know, try to
走到他们身边，试着和
befriend them. So this is this has been
他们交朋友。 所以，这就是
this throughine of my life is is trying
我人生的主线，那就是努力
to champion people who I feel were the
支持那些我觉得像
ones who were, you know, like me, you
我一样，被撞到
know, smashed up against the the bus
公交车
window.
窗户上的人们。
And you eventually went off to
然后你最终上了
university, college.
大学。   是的
Yes.
。
after college? investment banking.
大学毕业后你直接从事了什么职业？ 投资银行。
Okay. Interesting.
好的。 有趣的。
Ended up hating it for the passion.
最终却因为这份热情而憎恨它。
Explain.
解释。
Oh my god. I mean, talk about
我的天啊。 我的意思是，说到那种把
eat you up, spit you out culture, you
你吃掉又吐出来的文化，你
know, like here's the best here here's
知道，就像这是最好的，这是
how here's how I reminisce about
如何，这是我如何回忆
investment banking. My boss at the time
投资银行业。 我当时的老板
was 33 years old, right? [snorts] Uh
33岁，对吧？  [嗤之以鼻] 呃，
multi-millionaire. He was considered one
千万富翁。 他被认为是
of the top uh so the division I was in
顶尖人物之一，我所在的部门是
was uh was banks. We covered banks. So
银行部门。 我们报道了银行业。 所以
he was one of the top investment bankers
他是当时顶尖的投资银行家之一，
um you know covering banks but top
你知道，我们主要负责银行业务，但真的是顶尖的
investment banker right his wife was
投资银行家，对吧？当时
at the time that we were working on a
我们正在洽谈一笔
huge deal. It was the at that time it
大交易，而他的妻子正怀着孕。 那是当时
the history right of of just history.
历史上规模最大的二次发行，就在历史上。
But so it's a major deal. His wife is
但这可是件大事。 他妻子
pregnant, first child.
怀孕了，这是第一个孩子。
She's starting to give birth. He decides
她开始分娩了。 他决定
to come into work and he sends her to
来上班，然后把她送去了
the hospital. And he comes into work and
医院。 他来上班的那一刻，
I'll never forget it. He's he's he's
我永远不会忘记。 他，他，他正沿着
walking down this the aisle. I'm like in
这条过道走下去。 我感觉自己像被困在
a cubicle. He's got the office in front
一个隔间里。 他面前就是他的办公室
of me. is walking down the aisle and
。 他正沿着过道走着，
people are standing up like this
人们像这样站起来
[snorts]
（嗤笑），
like, "Yeah, this is that's right. You
好像在说：“对，就是这样。你
come here. This is the most important
来这里。这是最重要的
thing." Yeah, she let her go off and do
事。” 是的，她让她去做了
that. Right. That was the moment where I
。 正确的。 那一刻我
said, "This place is this is like this
脱口而出：“这个地方简直太
is crazy." You know, it's crazy. It's
疯狂了。” 你知道吗，这太疯狂了。 太
ridiculous. And so that was when I
荒谬了。 于是我
started thinking, "Okay, I need to I
开始想，“好吧，我
need to get out of here."
必须离开这里。”
And then you went and worked for Envir.
然后你就去 Envir 工作了。
No, I didn't I didn't go to Enver yet.
不，我还没有去过恩维尔。
Oh,
哦
okay. I went off to I did what everybody
好的。 我去了，做了每个人都会做的事
does. I went to business school.
。 我读的是商学院。
Ah, okay.
哦，好的。
And so went to business school. While I
于是，他去了商学院。 我
was so while I was at business school, I
在商学院读书期间，
met Enenver. I didn't start working for
遇到了 Enenver。 我一开始并没有为
him, but I met him.
他工作，但我认识了他。
So So he at that time multi-millionaire,
所以，他当时是千万富翁，
but he owned a ma a massive company in
但他在土耳其拥有一家规模庞大的公司
Turkey. He was trying to extend his
。 他当时正试图将
business in the United States. And when
业务拓展到美国。
I met him, it was a professional
我认识他的时候，我们之间是工作
relationship. And it was more so, hey,
关系。 而且更确切地说，嘿，
Paul, whenever I come to the United
保罗，每当我来
States, I'd love for you to help me to
美国的时候，我都希望你能帮我
schedule meetings or help for you uh
安排会议或者帮
help me to get booked into people
我联系一些人，
because I lived in Washington DC at the
因为我当时住在华盛顿特区，
time and Capitol Hill was there. lots of
国会山就在那里。 许多
senators and congress people. And so it
参议员和国会议员。 因此，
was easy for me to pick up the phone,
我很容易就能拿起电话，利用
work the the the network to get a
人脉关系安排一次会面，而这个人很
meeting with it could be Senator Hillary
可能是参议员希拉里·
Clinton. And so I was helping him at the
克林顿。 所以当时我在帮他
time. Then I came up with a concept to
。 然后我想到一个
start a nonprofit organization and I
成立非营利组织的想法，我
needed to raise funding or I wanted to
需要筹集资金，或者说我想
raise funding for it and I decided that
为此筹集资金，所以我决定
I would ask Enver to help me um on this.
请恩维尔帮我做这件事。
So that's when I started working for
于是，我就开始为
Enver.
恩维尔工作了。
How old are you at that age?
你那时多大了？
I don't know. That's uh I'm 30. I'm in
我不知道。 嗯，我30岁了。我正处于
the in the 30 zone.
30岁这个年龄段。
In your early in your early 30s, you
在你三十岁出头的时候，你
start your your matchmaking company.
创办了自己的婚介公司。   是什么让
connected with you inside and made you
你对婚介如此
obsessed with anything to go and study
着迷，以至于投入这么多年去研究它、追求它？这一定是因为它与
because of your experiences your biases
你的经历、你的偏见，以及
your in a in a very particular way
你自身非常特殊的原因产生了某种联系。
because I'm somewhat interested in it
因为我对婚介有点兴趣，
but I wouldn't dedicate my I wouldn't
但我不会
dedicate that kind of attention to it.
投入那么多精力。
So what was it about you that resonated
那么，你身上究竟有什么特质，能
in such a way?
以这种方式将人们凝聚在一起？
Fair. You you know thinking about this
公平的。 你知道，
for the first time is I'm actually
我第一次思考这个问题时，其实是把
connecting it to what you asked me with
它和你问我的
regard to how I grew up right cuz to me
关于我的成长经历的问题联系起来了，因为在我看来，
nearly every person who comes to a
几乎每个去找
matchmaker cuz keep in mind you're
媒人的人，记住，你
probably spending 10 to$20,000
可能要花1万到2万美元来
you know for for matchmaking services.
做媒服务。
you're probably allocating six to 12
你可能要花费六到十
months of your life to walk through that
二个月的时间来完成这个
process. It it is it's a lot, right? And
过程。 确实很多，对吧？ 对
to me, every the kernel of every client
我来说，每个客户的内心深处都有
there's a feeling of hopelessness.
一种绝望感。
There's a feeling of this is my last
感觉就像这是我最后的
shot, you know. There's a feeling of I
机会了，你知道吗？ 有一种感觉，
am alone, you know, in in in this. And
你知道吗，我孤身一人，独自面对这一切。 而
that's where I resonated. You know, I
这正是我产生共鸣的地方。 你知道，我
always talk about I, you know, I don't
总是谈到我，你知道，我不
know in in business, you know, we talk
知道在商业中，你知道，我们谈到
about this fifth why, right? The why
这第五个为什么，对吧？
that makes you cry. The the why that
那个让你哭泣的原因。 为什么
when you're thinking about a customer,
当你思考客户时，
what are they thinking about at night?
他们晚上在想什么？   是
What's keeping them up right at night?
什么让他们夜不能寐？
And if you as an entrepreneur or a
如果你作为一名企业家或
business owner, if you can help to solve
企业主，能够帮助他们解决
that problem that's keeping them up at
那个让他们
night, the why that's making them cry,
夜不能寐、让他们哭泣的问题，
well, that's that's the the secret
那么，这就是成功的
sauce. But the key is that you have to
秘诀。 但关键是你要
be passionate about that, right? Because
对这件事充满热情，对吧？ 因为
it's going to take you a lot of, you
你需要投入大量的
know, innovations and a lot of time, a
创新、时间和
lot of energy to figure out what the
精力才能找到成功的
formula is. But for me, that that was
秘诀。 但对我来说，事情就是这样
what it was. It it was there was like
。 当时的感觉就像是，我快要
this level of like I'm I'm giving up
放弃
hope, you know, I'm just I'm I'm just
希望了，你知道吗，我真的，我真的受够了
done. And also it was for a particular
。 而且它是为特定的
avatar which I think is also important
虚拟形象设计的，我认为这
for a particular customer. So, you know
对特定的客户来说也很重要。 所以，你知道
what I've always learned in business is
我在商业中一直学到的一点是，
that you can't serve everyone, right?
你不可能服务所有人，对吧？
So, it's important to find a particular
所以，找到特定的
customer, a specific demographic, a
客户、特定的人群、
customer avatar, right? And look for the
客户画像非常重要，对吧？ 找出
deepest pain point within that
该特定用户画像中最深层的痛点
particular avatar. Now, when I got into
。 当我进入
the matchmaking space, I was the first
婚介行业时，我是第一个，
or what the matchmaking institute says,
或者用婚介机构的话来说，
I was the first full-time black
我是美国第一个全职黑人
matchmaker
婚介师
in the United States. Okay.
。 好的。
In matchmaking, what a lot of people
在婚介领域，很多人
don't like to talk about what was
不愿意谈论的是，
segregation happening in the matchmaking
婚介
space. And what was happening is that in
行业存在着严重的性别隔离现象。 当时的情况是，
serviced by matchmakers for a variety of
由于各种原因，黑人女性尤其得不到媒人的服务
reasons, but they were not being
，但实际上她们根本没有得到任何
serviced at all. So my first customer,
服务。 所以我的第一位客户，
my first avatar were black women in
我的第一个目标群体，
particular in the uh we call it the DMV,
特别是居住在我们称之为 DMV（华盛顿
DC, Maryland, Virginia area. And so
特区、马里兰州、弗吉尼亚州）地区的黑人女性。 所以，
within the avatar, right? And so it was
虚拟化身方面存在一个非常具体的痛点，对吧？ 所以，当时的气氛是
hopelessness, but it wasn't just
绝望的，但不仅仅是
hopelessness. Now that I've described,
绝望。 现在我已经描述完了，
you know, the avatar, right? This is
你知道，就是化身，对吧？ 这个
someone who most likely
人很可能受过
she's highly educated. She she's making
高等教育。 她赚了
great money. She has uh a a child, you
很多钱。 她有个孩子，你
know, um she is incredible
知道，嗯，她真是个很棒的人，很适合
um match for someone. So So she became
某个人。 所以她成了
my first she became my first client and
我的第一个客户，
I was passionate. You know why? Because
我当时非常热情。 你知道为什么吗？ 因为
she was my sister-in-law. She was my
她是我嫂子。 她是我
auntie, you know, she was my cousin. I
姑姑，你知道，她也是我表妹。 我
know her. I live with her. I've grown up
认识她。 我和她住在一起。 我从小就
with her. That was why I was so, you
和她一起长大。 这就是为什么我
know, so passionate about her.
对她如此、如此热情的原因。
What is what is the relationship your
你和父母的关系如何？
your parents had and how has that
这种关系对
influenced your work?
你的工作有何影响？   是
Yeah, great great one. They have had an
啊，非常棒。
relationship, you know, and and and not
你知道，他们之间有着非常深厚的感情，而且不仅仅是
just my parents, but my grandparents.
我的父母，还有我的祖父母。
It's no surprise, is it? Because then
这不足为奇，不是吗？ 因为
you've had this, you know, staggering
你知道，你和
long relationship with Jill. It's funny
吉尔之间有着一段漫长而惊人的关系。 有趣的是，
how that, you know, those generational
这种代际
cycles play out over and over again,
循环总是不断重复上演，
right?
对吧？   是的
Yeah. And and that and that's it. That's
。 就这样，就这些了。 就是这样。
it. It's like, let's break the cycle,
就像，让我们打破这个循环，
you know, we we can break the cycle.
你知道，我们可以打破这个循环。
playing out, you know, with my wife
你知道，那是我和妻子
Jill. Her parents
吉尔之间发生的事情的一部分。 她的父母
incredibly strong, right? her
非常坚强，对吧？ 她的
grandparents on both sides incredibly
祖父母，无论哪一方，都非常
strong, incredibly loving.
坚强，非常慈爱。
It's an interesting question for anybody
对于现在正在收听这段音频的每个人来说，这是一个很有趣的问题，
listening to this now, which is like how
那就是：如果你正处于一段感情关系中
much does your relationship currently,
，那么你目前的感情关系在多大程度上与
if you're in one, mirror that of your
你
parents? And I think about, you know,
父母的感情关系相似？ 我觉得，
even the in my team here, the people
即使在我所在的团队里，那些
that have the best relationships in my
人际关系最好的人
team,
，
their parents have the best
他们的父母
relationships and their partners'
人际关系也最好，他们伴侣的
parents have the best relationships.
父母人际关系也最好。
like just that solid best friend type
就像那种铁哥们儿般的亲密
vibes, multi-deade best friend vibes in
氛围，父母身上那种失去多位挚友的氛围
their parents.
。   是的
Yes.
。
That's interesting.
那很有意思。   是的
Yeah. And and I so um I agree. I think
。 我同意。 我认为
if we did that, we did a you know
如果我们进行一项
longitudinal study around that,
纵向研究，
we would find that to be precise. But
就会发现结果很准确。 但
part of what I think is driving it is I
我认为部分原因是，
mean you could go back and look at
你可以回顾一下
attachment styles, but I think largely
依恋类型，但我认为主要原因是
what's what's driving that is is seeing
看到
what love looks like modeled before you,
爱情在你面前的体现，
right? And know that it's not always
对吧？ 要知道，它并不总是
uh what we consider to be loveydvey. It
我们认为的那种爱情。 这
can be contentious. A matter of fact,
可能会引发争议。 事实上，
disagreements and arguments are
分歧和争论是
important are are are are critical,
重要且至关重要的，
right? because you need to almost break
对吧？ 因为你需要几乎彻底
down the relationship in order to gain
摧毁一段关系，才能获得
the skills to to to to bring it back up,
重建关系的技巧，
right? And that's [clears throat] what
对吧？ 而这正是它更强大的原因（清嗓子）
makes it stronger. And so I think the
。 所以我认为
modeling is is is key.
建模是关键。
It's so true. So true. And I've it took
说得太对了。 如此真实。 直到
me until I was 25 years to old to figure
我25岁才明白这一点
this out. That modeling point that the
。 这一点表明，
first model you've been given of love is
你最早感受到的爱的榜样是
your parents. So you believe that to be
你的父母。 所以你认为
the truth about any person you then meet
你之后遇到的每个人都是如此
in your life. And so you I I can
。 所以，我
remember like almost in high definition
几乎能清晰地记得，我
in my mind this image of looking over at
看着
my dad sat on the sofa and my mom just
爸爸坐在沙发上，妈妈
screaming at him and thinking I'd
对他大喊大叫，我当时想，我
[__] hate to be this guy. And then I
真不想成为他那样的人。 然后我
go into life and I just avoid
进入生活，就一直回避“是”
Yes.
。
avoid every I'm obsessed about having
避免所有我执着于
control of
控制的事情，我的
I mean
意思是，
I've heard you talk about this before.
我以前听你谈过这件事。   是的
Yes. Yeah. I was going to say yes. I
。 是的。 我本来打算答应的。 我的
mean this this is that is prototype
意思是，这就是所谓的原型
avoidant.
回避。
Yeah, that's me.
对，那是我。
Attachment style. Yeah.
附件样式。 是的。
Right. And and what's was so interesting
正确的。 而让
to me about attachment style which by
我对依恋类型如此感兴趣的是，顺便说一句，
Lavine wrote a phenomenal book called
拉文博士写了一本非常棒的书，叫做《
attached right on this and I recommend
依恋》，专门讲这个，我推荐
for for everyone is you know there
给大家。你知道，
attachment. You have secure, you have
依恋主要分为三种类型。 有安全型、
anxious, and then you have avoidant.
焦虑型和回避型人格。
Right. And when you think about this,
正确的。 当你思考这个问题时，
it's precisely what you just said,
正如你刚才所说，
Stephen, is that when you think of how
斯蒂芬，当你回想
you first saw love and you saw it
你第一次看到爱，看到爱的
modeled and you saw it relate to you,
形象，看到爱与你之间的联系时，
right? Was it one of which was secure in
对吧？ 其中一个地方是否让
that you felt like you would be, you
你感到安全，让你
know, if you were hurt, you could go to
觉得，如果你受伤了，你可以去
a place for safety, right? You would be
一个安全的地方，对吗？ 你会受到
caressed, right? you'd be you'd you'd be
爱抚，对吗？ 你会得到
cared for. You know, that's secure. But
照顾。 你知道，这样很安全。 但
then you move to the avoidant, right?
之后你又会转向回避型人格，对吧？   当时
Where it was you almost having to self
你几乎需要自己
soothe yourself, right? Which then
安抚自己，对吧？ 这
pushes you away from wanting to have
会让你更不想和
have anything to do with that. And you
这件事有任何瓜葛。 然后你就会
become, you know what's interesting? The
变成，你知道什么很有趣吗？
the top entrepreneurs
顶尖的企业家（这只是我的猜测和观察）都
are avoidance
在回避问题，
because they've had to develop the
因为他们必须培养
skills to self- sustain themselves,
自给自足的技能，
right? They've had to rely on
对吗？ 他们不得不依靠
themselves. People who are avoidant
自己。 回避型人格的人
don't trust easily, but you trust
不容易信任别人，但你相信
yourself, right? So you look at that and
自己，对吗？ 所以你看到它就会
you say, "Oh my god, like this came from
说：“我的天哪，这简直就像是
me as a child." Like it's it's
我小时候写的。” 简直太
incredible. And then with the anxious,
不可思议了。 至于焦虑的人，
the anxious is really interesting
焦虑的人真的很有意思，
because the anxious was typically a lot
因为焦虑的人通常和
of parents like my situation where your
我的父母一样，很多父母都一直在
parents worked all the time. So when
工作。 所以当
they were home, they would be there to
他们在家的时候，他们会给
give you the love, but they couldn't be
你爱，但他们不可能一直待在
home all the time because they had to be
家里，因为他们
they had to work. So then you had to
必须工作。 所以你当时需要
self soothe a little bit. So then you
稍微安慰一下自己。 所以你开始
became anxious about their love.
对他们的爱情感到焦虑。
Needy.
贫困。
Needy. And this is the person who's like
贫困。 这个人总是给
texting you all the time like I know in
你发短信，我知道
the past you must have had the the
你以前肯定有过
girlfriend was like, "Stephen, where are
女朋友，她会问：“斯蒂芬，
you? Stephen, where are you?"
你在哪儿？斯蒂芬，你在哪儿？”
No comment. [laughter]
没有意见。  [笑声]
Stephen, where are you? Where are you?
斯蒂芬，你在哪里？ 你在哪里？
Where are you? Right. All of that shows
你在哪里？ 正确的。 所有这些特质都会
up as adults, right? Uh and and also
在成年后显现出来，对吧？ 嗯，还有，但是，
this is but but I guess long story short
但是我想长话短说，
is to the point of when we've recognized
当我们意识到
with someone who is secure is so
与一个有安全感的人建立恋爱关系如此
important because you can shift your
重要的原因时，因为作为成年人，你可以改变自己的
style as an adult. You can be avoidant,
风格。 你可以有回避型依恋，
be in a relationship with someone who's
与安全型依恋的人建立恋爱关系，
secure and adapt to a secure attachment.
并适应安全型依恋。
Do you notice that? Do you notice that
你注意到这一点了吗？ 你有没有注意到，
people who are avoidant tend to go for
回避型人格的人往往会选择性格
for people that are more secure? No,
比较自信的人？ 不，
they go for for the anxious.
他们瞄准的是焦虑的人。
Interesting.
有趣的。
Right. Yeah. Yeah.
正确的。 是的。 是的。
So they go for needy people, [laughter]
所以他们会去帮助有需要的人，[笑声]
right? Because because Yeah. Because I
对吧？ 因为，是的。 因为我的
mean becomes a bit of a you know they're
意思是，这就有点像你知道的，他们在
chasing them and they're they're because
追赶他们，而他们，因为
you know you think about this. If you're
你知道，你会想到这一点。 如果你是
avoidant, you're pretty much self-
回避型人格，你基本上就能
sustained, right? But if someone is
自给自足，对吧？ 但是，如果有人感到
anxious, they're aggressively courting
焦虑，他们就会积极地追求
you, right? So they're pushing to be in
你，对吗？ 所以他们是想挤进
your space, right? So the secure
你的领域，对吧？ 所以，
unfortunately becomes boring for so many
对很多人来说，安全感不幸地变得乏味了
people.
。
Safe, vanilla.
安全，味道平淡。
It's so true. I can't [laughter] believe
说得太对了。 我简直不敢相信
how true this is,
这是真的，
you know. Um but but but secure is where
你知道吗？（笑） 嗯，但是，安全才是关键
it's at. You know, it's where it's at.
。 你知道，这就是重点所在。
You want two secure people.
你需要两个有安全感的人。
You want a secure and anyone else. a
你想要一个安全可靠的环境，其他人也一样。
strong secure
强大的安全措施
can help bring could could help bring
可以帮助把
anyone over too. But but also you know
任何人带过来。 但是，你也知道，
an avoidant and anxious can can also uh
回避型和焦虑型人格的人也可能……
you know work. It's ultimately to me
你知道，工作。 对我来说，归根结底，关键在于
it's it's it's about that effort.
努力。   例如，
Is there such a way to so if I'm an
如果我是一个
avoidant for example or I'm an anxious
回避型人格或焦虑型人格，有
is there work I can do myself to become
没有办法让我自己成为
a secure without having to meet a secure
一个安全型人格，而无需遇到一个安全型人格
and have them bring me over?
并让他们把我带过去？   是的
Yes, absolutely. One of the top things
，绝对的。
someone who is avoidant can work on is
回避型人格障碍患者最需要努力改善的方面之一就是
their emotional intimacy.
情感亲密关系。
And that begins with simply recognizing
而这一切首先要从认识
their emotions, your emotions, and
他们的情绪、你自己的情绪并
articulating them. It's it seem it
表达出来开始。 看起来很
actually seems easy, but it's incredibly
简单，但实际上却极具
challenging.
挑战性。
So uncomfortable.
太不舒服了。   感觉
So uncomfortable,
很不舒服，
especially for a man.
尤其是对男人来说。   是的
Yes. So for example I could say Stephen
。 例如，我可以问斯蒂芬，
how do you truly how do you feel right
你现在感觉如何？
now in this moment very inspired and
此刻，你是不是很有灵感，也
very keen to learn.
很渴望学习？
Okay.
好的。
Well but very yeah
嗯，好吧，
okay well I mean you did that
我的意思是，你
effortlessly right but but but
毫不费力地就做到了，对吧？但是，
now the next challenge would be okay
现在下一个挑战是，好吧，
well do that with your you know with
和你的伴侣一起做这件事，在让
spaces where you feel vulnerable. It
你感到脆弱的地方做这件事。 要
becomes very very challenging to say how
表达
you feel, how someone makes you feel.
自己的感受，或者别人带给你的感受，会变得非常非常困难。
It makes perfect sense because there was
这完全说得通，因为
a void in my childhood of parenting
我的童年时期缺乏父母的关爱，
which I I've always said has made made
我一直认为正是这种缺失造就了
me an entrepreneur. But in that void as
我成为一名企业家。 但在那份空白中
well, there's a void of like um learning
，也存在着一种学习
affection.
情感的空白。
Ah
啊，原来
so I you know I still call my parents by
我一直都直呼父母的
their first names. I've never called
名字。 我从来没叫过
them mom and dad. I we we weren't like
他们爸爸妈妈。 我小时候，我们不像现在这样，
there was no like I love you or like
没有“我爱你”或者
hugging or stuff stuff like that
拥抱之类的亲密举动
especially in my childhood. So learning
。 所以，
later in life to then to be emotional
后来我才学会表达自己的情绪，
and to express how I'm feeling and to if
学会表达自己的感受。如果
your girlfriend says what's wrong or you
女朋友问我怎么了，或者
know how do you feel about this I you
问我对此有什么感觉，
know I'd often just lie about how I was
我以前常常会撒谎，只是为了
feeling just for keep things nice and
维持表面的
calm
平静。
um but I defin you know it's definitely
但我必须承认，这绝对是
something I've had to learn
我必须学习的东西。
right but I I I can see that that so I
不过，我能看出
mean you're a life learner like you're
你是一个终身学习者，就像
you're a student of life so I can see
一个人生学生一样。所以我能看出，
that you have be not even begun you've
你甚至还没开始，就已经
you've done the work, right? But for so
做了很多功课了，对吧？ 但对于如此
many avoidance,
多的逃避行为，
I'd say begun.
我认为已经开始了。
Begun. Okay. So, but for so many
开始。 好的。 所以，由于种种
avoidance, that work has not yet begun.
逃避行为，这项工作尚未开始。
And being able to identify the emotion,
能够识别这种情绪，
right? And and and the feeling, too, cuz
对吧？ 还有感觉，因为
you know, and even distinguish between
你知道，甚至要区分
the emotion and the feeling, right? But
情绪和感觉，对吧？ 但是，
to be able to to distinguish that and
能够区分这一点，并且
then to be able to articulate that is so
能够清楚地表达这一点，是
incredibly important because without
非常重要的，因为没有这一点，
that you cannot have the emotional
你就无法拥有情感上的
intimacy. And if you can't have
亲密感。 如果你无法建立
emotional intimacy, you just simply
情感上的亲密关系，你就根本
can't have a relationship. You just
无法建立一段关系。 你根本
can't. You you have acquaintances, you
做不到。 你有熟人，你
know, you have co-workers, you know, um
知道，你有同事，你知道，嗯，
you have uh uh situationships,
你有一些暧昧关系，
you know, but you don't have
你知道，但你没有
relationships.
恋爱关系。
That is a amazing sound bite.
这段录音真是精彩绝伦。
Please cut that into a real for Tik Tok
请把这段话剪辑成一段正式视频，供TikTok
team listening. Um, so there's gender
团队收听。 嗯，这里也存在性别
differences here as well because of of
差异，因为
my friends, both women and men, I know
我的朋友们，无论男女，我都知道
for a fact that my male friends usually
我的男性朋友通常
just push for like an easy life.
都只想过轻松的生活。   是的
Yeah.
。
They just want, you know, if their
他们只是想知道，他们的
partner is expressing emotional um
伴侣是否在表达
feelings or is expressing their emotions
情感，或者是否在
towards them. Most of my male friends
向他们表达情感。 我的大多数男性朋友
will see that as an attack,
都会把这看作是一种攻击，
you know, and like they just don't want
你知道，他们根本不想
to go there. It's it's this energy that
谈这个。 正是这种气质让
men just don't like. So, I was watching
男人感到不悦。 所以，我
Twitter video before I came down here
来这里之前在推特上看到一个很有趣的视频，视频里有个
and it's this woman, she's cooked dinner
女人
for her husband, and she's proving that
给她丈夫做了晚饭，结果证明
men just won't tell you the truth. She
男人就是不会跟你说实话。 她
puts loads of salt in it to make it
往里面放了很多盐，让它变得
taste awful. And she walks into the
很难吃。 她走进
front room while he's watching the game
客厅，当时他正在看比赛，
and she goes, "Try this, hun. Tell me
然后她说：“亲爱的，试试这个。告诉我
what you think." And you see his face
你的想法。” 然后你看到他
just wink and it's [laughter] [__]
眨眨眼，真是[笑]恶心死了
disgusting. And he goes, "Yeah, be
。 他接着说：“嗯，要
good."
乖。”
And for me, it's summed up, man. It's
对我来说，这就是全部了。
like we just want to avoid the the heat.
我们好像只是想躲避酷暑。
Like
就像
we we literally literally, you know, so
我们真的，你知道，所以
I have a theory on this, right? So I'm
我对此有一个理论，对吧？ 所以，我
I'm testing this one out, right? But but
正在测试这个，对吧？ 但
I call it the feedback loop theory. So
我称之为反馈回路理论。
my wife was in HR.
我妻子之前在人力资源部门工作。   是的
Yeah.
。   在
Before she joined me in the matchmaking
她加入我的婚介
space. And one of the things that they
行业之前。 在
would do uh in their company, she worked
她工作的
in this law firm is that they would uh
这家律师事务所里，他们会做的一件事就是
you know extensive feedback during the
在
review period. Extensive feedback. So
绩效考核期间提供广泛的反馈。 广泛的反馈。 所以
you know how was your year? How did you
你知道你这一年过得怎么样吗？ 你的
perform? All of these these KPIs, right?
表现如何？ 这些都是关键绩效指标，对吧？
And that feedback would translate into
而这种反馈会转化为
higher performance. I mean just bottom
更高的绩效。 我的意思是，就事论事
line. And what I've noticed with women
。 我注意到，女性
typically typically with women is that
通常会在经历
whenever there's a romantic experience,
浪漫体验后，
with like 10 of their friends.
与大约 10 个朋友分享这种浪漫体验。
You know, it's like go out on a date,
你知道，就像出去约会一样，
the WhatsApp group knows everything
WhatsApp 群组里的人都知道约会当天
that's happening in in on on the date.
发生的一切。
And then there's a debrief of the date,
然后是对约会的总结，
there's an analysis of the date, here's
是对约会的分析，比如
what he did, here's what I wore, blah
他做了什么，我穿了什么，
blah blah blah blah. This happens for
等等等等。 这种情况持续了
three days. constant feedback and that
三天。 不断的反馈
feedback ends up making women I think on
最终会让女性
average better daters, right? Better
平均而言成为更好的约会者，对吧？ 更有
equipped to deal and manage in
能力处理和管理
relationships. Now, Stephen, when you
人际关系。 史蒂芬，你
were single, tell me this. If you were
单身的时候，跟我说说这件事吧。 如果你
going on a date, right, who did you talk
要去约会，你会和谁谈论
to about the date?
约会的事？
Nobody. [laughter]
没有。  [笑声]
See, go. Yeah. And so it's it's all it's
看，走吧。 是的。 所以，这一切都只是
all in your head. It's like, okay,
你的想象。 就好像，好吧，
I might tell one of my friends. I might
我可能会告诉我的一个朋友。 我可能会
say, "Oh, I saw this person the other
说：“哦，我前几天晚上看到这个人了
night." You know, when I was single, I
。” 你知道，当我单身的时候，我
would have gone, you know, I saw Ruby
就会去，你知道，我
like 3 days ago and she was that was it
大概三天前见过Ruby，她当时就很
was fun. Yeah.
高兴。 是的。   是的
Yeah. He was like, "All right, cool."
。 他当时说：“好的，酷。”   是的
Yeah. That's it. Move on. Yeah.
。 就是这样。 继续前行。 是的。
[laughter] Yeah.
[笑声] 是的。   就这样。
And that's it. There's There's no
没有
feedback. And think about this. Think
反馈。 想想看。 想想看，这
about not that just happening on one
不仅仅是发生在某
date, but that happening month after
一天，而是月复
month, year after year, 10, 15 years of
一月、年复一年、10年、15年，期间
no feedback. We're all in our head. we
没有任何反馈。 我们都活在自己的思绪里。 我们
have no idea like how to perform, how to
不知道该如何表现，如何
up our performance, and that impacts
提高表现，这会影响
what happens when we eventually get into
我们最终进入
the relationship. So, I I think the
恋爱关系时的情况。 所以，我认为
feedback loop, there's really something
反馈循环确实有其作用
to it. And I've noticed it's primarily a
。 我注意到这主要是一种
a gender difference.
性别差异。
So, are you saying also that because
所以，你的意思是，因为
women are have a community where they're
女性有一个可以
discussing stuff, they're discussing
讨论各种事情、讨论
feelings and what happened and d they
感受和发生的事情的群体，所以她们会
try and bring that same energy to a man
尝试把这种能量带给一个
who's just not used to it. And he goes,
不习惯这种氛围的男性。 然后他说：
"Fucking hell." Like I I don't know.
“该死。” 我不知道。
Like I You know what I mean? And he's
就像我，你知道我的意思吗？ 他
just like trying to avoid going there
只是想尽量避免去那里，
because he's never really had to go
因为他以前从来没有真正去过
there before.
那里。   他从来不需要这样做
Ne never had to. Never had to. When you
。 从来不需要。 当你
dig into the data, and this is what I
深入研究数据时，这就是我
love about love, like in particular, I
热爱爱情的原因，尤其是，我
always say that my expertise is
总是说我的专长是
relationship science, right? I like to
关系科学，对吧？ 我喜欢
look at the science [snorts] of love and
研究爱情的科学原理（嗤之以鼻），
look at how that impacts how we show up
看看它如何影响我们展现自我的方式
and why we show up. And the beauty of
以及我们展现自我的原因。 科学的美妙之处
science is that if you can change the
在于，如果你能改变
the formula, not not necessarily
公式（不一定是
formula, if you can change the equation,
公式本身），如果你能改变方程式，那么
right, you change the result. And that's
你就能改变结果。 这就是它的
the beautiful thing. So if you are
美妙之处。 所以，如果你正处于
someone who is in a relationship and
恋爱关系中，却不
you're unsure how to communicate,
知道如何沟通，
there's certain things that you could
你可以改变一些事情
change to make the communication
来
stronger, make the relationship better.
加强沟通，改善关系。
Tell me what those are.
告诉我那些是什么。
Oh my god, there's there's so many.
我的天哪，真的太多了。
clients in terms of like communication,
在沟通、
conflict resolution?
冲突解决等方面，哪些基本要素对您和您的客户行之有效？
Okay, great great question. Uh, okay.
好的，问得好。 呃，好的。
So, a couple things and even with uh not
所以，有几件事，
only with my clients but but with my
不仅对我的客户，也对我的
wife, you know, so this this seems so
妻子，你知道，这看起来很
basic. I think it's talked about but not
基本。 我认为人们谈论过
even talked about enough is Gary
加里·
Chapman's five love languages.
查普曼的五种爱的语言，但还不够多。
It seems so simple but it literally
这看似简单，却彻底
changed my marriage. So, by, you know,
改变了我的婚姻。 所以，你知道，
typically in marriages, not committed
婚姻中通常存在所谓的“五年之痒”和“七年之痒”，而不是指恋爱
relationships, but marriages where you
关系中的“七年之痒”，在婚姻中，你会
literally see separation rates and
发现分居率和
divorce rates increase at that five and
离婚率在五年和
sevenyear mark, right? You also see it
七年时显著上升，对吧？ 你也会看到这种情况
happen when uh they become when
发生在
marriages become you become empty
婚姻关系破裂，子女离家后，成为空
nesters. Your you know kids go off to
巢老人的时候。 你知道孩子们都要去
school. But right around that five and
上学。 但就在我五岁到
seven year mark, I was sleeping on the
七年大的时候，我开始睡在
couch at my house. Like it was not good,
家里的沙发上。
you know, in our household. And this was
你知道，在我们家，情况不太好。 这件事虽然
so small but so significant is I bought
很小，但意义却很重大：我买了
Dr. Gary Chapman's five love languages,
加里·查普曼博士的《爱的五种语言》，
right? Which outlines, right, five ways
对吧？ 文中概述了
that we recognize and see love. But here
我们认识和看待爱的五种方式。 但这
was the power of it. The power of it was
就是它的力量所在。 这件事的起因是，
that my wife, I thought she was spoiled
我觉得我妻子被宠坏了，
because all she wanted was gifts. Like
因为她想要的只是礼物。
she was like, "Buy me this. Buy me that.
她就像在说：“给我买这个。给我买那个。今天
It's my birthday. Buy me this. It's
是我的生日。给我买这个。今天是
Christmas. Buy me this. It's Monday. Buy
圣诞节。给我买这个。今天是星期一。给
me this." Right? It was buy me buy me.
我买这个。” 正确的？ 是“买我，买我”。
Right. And I thought to myself, Jesus,
正确的。 我心想，天哪，
she's spoiled. Like, this is crazy. So,
她被宠坏了。 这简直太疯狂了。 那
what do I do, Stephen? I bet you you
我该怎么办，斯蒂芬？ 我敢肯定你
would do the same thing. You know what I
也会这么做。 你知道我
did?
做了什么吗？
I said, "I'm not going to buy you
我说：“我不会给你买
anything.
任何东西。
You know, cuz you're spoiled. I'm going
你知道，因为你被宠坏了。我要
to change this behavior. You know, I'm
改变这种习惯。你知道，我
not going to buy you a thing. So, what
不会给你买任何东西。”那么，如果到了
happens when it's her birthday, it's
她的生日、
Christmas, it's the anniversary, it's
圣诞节、结婚纪念日、
Monday, and I'm not buying her anything.
星期一，而我什么都不给她买，会
Oh, man. Like, hell, it becomes hell.
发生什么呢？哦，天哪。简直糟透了。
But it was Dr. Gary Chapman's book that
但正是加里·查普曼博士的书让
helped me understand that the way that
我明白，
my wife grew up, the way that she saw
我妻子从小到大感受到的
love through her parents were through
爱，是通过
gifts. Her father spoiled her to death,
礼物来表达的。她父亲把她宠坏了，
right? And her father loved her and
对吧？她父亲爱她，并
through gift, through giftgiving. So she
通过礼物来表达爱，倾注爱意。所以她从小就
as a little girl is growing up thinking,
觉得，
okay, you know, I get the doll, I get
好吧，你知道，我得到了这个娃娃，我得到了这个
this, I get this, right? This is love,
，我得到了这个，对吧？这就是爱，
this is love, this is love. Her love
这就是爱，这就是爱。她表达爱的
language is legitimately gifts.
方式就是送礼物。
I had to understand that fundamentally
我必须从根本上理解这一点，
to understand that this is how she will
才能明白这就是她
see that I love her. It's not just
感受到我爱的方式。爱不仅仅是
simply through maybe what's you know uh
通过礼物。 也许你知道，嗯，
you know acts of service which is which
你知道，服务行为，也就是
is my love language
我的爱的语言，对吧？
right do something on my behalf
为我做点什么
[laughter]
[笑]。
right so I would do something on her
所以，我会为她做点什么，对吧？
behalf right but no it it was it's gifts
但是不，对
and then for her to know okay for me
她来说，是礼物。然后让她知道，好吧，对我来说是
it's acts of service so if she you know
服务行为。所以，如果她，你知道，
she was big on gifts giving me gifts and
她很喜欢送我礼物，而
I was like I don't I don't I don't
我却觉得，我，我，我接受不了，
resonate with this you know I don't I
你知道，我不懂
get this. And so f the understanding
。所以，
truly understanding
真正理解
your partner's love language
伴侣的爱的语言，
and then giving them love in that
然后用这种语言表达爱，这才是
language is a gamecher. And a quick way
关键。快速
to determine some someone's love
判断一个人的爱的
language is just observe how they show
语言的方法就是观察他们如何向
love to the people they love. Right?
所爱之人表达爱。对吧？
What do they do? Right? That's that's a
他们会做什么？对吧？这就是一个
quick way. So so so love languages game
快速的方法。所以，爱的语言真的
changer. game changer, right? So, so
能改变游戏规则，对吧？所以，
that's one. Um, secondly is to I think
这是第一点。嗯，第二点是，我认为
to to understand that you you need to
要明白，你需要
argue, right? But great relationships
争吵，对吧？但美好的关系
are bids. You're putting in bids. It's a
是不断的。你们在不断地表达爱意。就像一场
constant tennis match. That's a great
持续的网球比赛。 比赛。这才是美好的
relationship. Constant tennis match. So,
关系。就像一场永不停歇的网球赛。
what that means is that you are showing
这意味着你要
through your action, through your love
通过行动、用爱的
language, through your words, etc. But
语言、言语等等来表达你对
partner. And you're doing that
伴侣的爱。你要持续不断地这样做
over and over again. And what your
。你的
partner is going to be doing is they're
伴侣会把
going to hit that ball back to you. And
球打回来，你也会把球打回来。
them. But you have to remember this one
但你必须记住一点
thing. Sometimes you have to hit the
：有时候，你得把
ball five times over, right, the net
球打过网五次，他们才会回击
before they return the ball to you. And
。
ultimately what that means is that you
最终，这意味着你
have to consistently remind your
必须不断地提醒你的
partner. So you could be I'm 21 years
伴侣。比如，我已经结婚21年了
into my marriage. People think all right
。人们可能会想，好吧，
you're 21 you're good. You don't have to
你都21年了，一切都好。你
do anything now right smooth sailing. No
现在什么都不用做了，一帆风顺吧。不，
when I get home today I am still showing
我今天回家后仍然会
up recognizing that I have to
提醒自己，我必须
continually put those bids in. You know
不断地付出。你知道，
I always say it's like Janet Jackson
我常说，这就像珍妮·杰克逊的歌一样，
what have you done for me lately? That's
你最近为我做了什么？这才是
truly what a relationship is, is that
真正的关系。 就是，
it's constantly it's this constant
它一直都是这样，一直都是这样
constant, right? And then part of that
，对吧？然后，这个
that constant too, and maybe this is
恒定的一部分，也许这只是
just a third concept, super simple, but
第三个概念，非常简单，那就是有
intentional time. Intentional time. So,
意识地安排时间。有意识地安排时间。所以，
so what what I find really interesting
我觉得真正有趣的
is you look at how much time we spend
是，看看我们和
with our our partners or our spouse,
伴侣或配偶相处的时间，平均
it's one to two hours a day. On a on
每天只有一到两个小时。平均而言
average, the average married couple
，已婚夫妇
spends one to two hours per day. So you
每天也只有一到两个小时。
think about that, you're probably
想想看，你和
spending more time with the bus driver
公交车司机相处的时间可能
than you are with with with your spouse.
比和配偶相处的时间还长。
And [snorts] then in the one to two
[嗤之以鼻] 那么，在这短短的一两个
hours, what are you actually doing? It's
小时里，你们到底在干什么呢？
like ships passing in the night. You
就像夜航的船只擦肩而过。你
know, no real conversation. One's
知道，没有真正的交流。一个人
watching TV in this side, one's on the
在这边看电视，另一个人在
computer over here. No real
那边玩电脑。没有真正的
communication. And what ends up
沟通。最终的结果
happening is you're not able to exchange
是，你们无法交流
ideas. You're not able to talk about,
想法。你们无法谈论
you know, dreams. You're not able to
梦想。你们无法谈论希望。
talk about hopes. You're not able to
你们无法
talk about your feelings. You know,
谈论感受。你知道，
you're not able to connect. Intentional
你们无法…… 能够建立联系。用心
time spent. I always say that, you know,
投入时间。我总是说，
effort always equals interest. But
付出总会有回报。但
whatever is important to you in life,
无论生活中什么对你来说重要，
you have to be intentional about
你都必须有意识地
spending time on it. you know, and that
投入时间。
includes the relationship. That includes
这当然也包括维系感情。所以，要
it. And so intentional time. So that may
用心投入时间。这可能
mean, okay, every Friday we're having
意味着，比如，我们每周五
dinner together or every night we're
一起吃晚饭，或者每天晚上都一起
having dinner. In my household, it's
吃晚饭。在我家，
every night we have dinner together as a
我们每天晚上都全家一起吃晚饭
family. I help I try to rearrange my
。我会尽量调整我的
schedule so that I'm at home with my
日程安排，以便能在家和
family having dinner. And if I get home
家人一起吃晚饭。如果我回家
too late to have dinner with my boys, my
太晚，没能和孩子们一起吃晚饭，
wife and I are having dinner at 11 p.m.
我和妻子会在晚上11点或12点吃晚饭
12 midnight, but we are communing
，但我们在一起交流
together, right? This is very important.
，对吧？这非常重要。
Uh, you know, we talk about, you know,
我们也会谈到
weekly dates, but the whole bottom line
每周约会，但关键
is spending time. This Saturday, my wife
在于花时间。这个星期六，
and I, we have a date, right? Yeah. 21
我和妻子有约会，对吧？是的。
years into our marriage, still planning
结婚21年了，我们仍然会计划
dates, still excited about the dates.
约会，仍然对约会充满期待。
It's intentional time spent. Intentional
这就是用心投入时间。 刻意
time spent. So the I mean there there's
投入时间。我的意思是，这里面有
there's so many concepts, but I would
很多概念，但我
say that if you just do those if if you
想说的是，如果你
just think about that those basics, love
只关注这些基本要素，比如爱的
language, right? Understanding that
语言，对吧？理解一段
relationships are always a bid. It's
关系永远是一个互动的过程。它
always a bid back and forth. Always. And
永远是一个来回的互动。永远如此。
sometimes you have to bid five, six
有时候，你可能需要尝试五六
times before you get the ball back,
次才能成功，
right? But it's always bid. And then
对吧？但它永远是一个互动的过程。然后，
it's intentional time spent. You you
你需要刻意投入时间。你
know you you typic you typically you
知道，通常情况下，你们会
typically grow together opposed to
共同成长，而不是
growing apart.
渐行渐远。
You're on the couch 5 years in, right?
五年后，你们还瘫在沙发上，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
of those things said is like
说了这么多，唯一能让你摆脱这种困境的方法就是
communication. You have to at some point
沟通。你必须在某个时候就
conversation about something.
某些事情进行一次艰难的对话。是的
Yes. um in business, in life, and in
。在商业、生活以及
everything. Um what I've noticed is most
所有事情上都是如此。我注意到，
of the issues I have in my life uh have
我生活中的大多数问题之所以会
become big issues because I didn't have
变成大问题，是因为我没有在
something sooner when I knew it was a
意识到
problem. So, I deferred it, I knocked it
问题存在的时候就进行坦诚的对话。所以，我拖延了，我拒绝了。 把它还
back, whatever. Um, the art of having a
回去，随便吧。嗯，在情绪激动、紧张的时候，如何
with a partner, with someone you love
与伴侣、爱人进行一次健康有效的对话，这
tension is something that I don't think
方面的艺术，我认为
we've talked about enough in in society,
在社会上讨论得还不够，
specifically men really struggle, I
尤其是男性，
think, with that. How does how does one
在这方面真的很难。怎样才能进行一次以解决
have a a good conflict resolution
冲突为
orientated conversation without, you
导向的对话，而不是
know, [__] screaming or running out
大喊大叫、逃跑
or whatever or blame, you know? Yeah.
或者互相指责呢？是的。是的。
Yeah. No, I hear you and and and I agree
不，我明白你的意思，我同意。我经常
and I and I I hear this this term uh
听到这个说法，我也
passed around a lot and I agree with it
很赞同，那就是：
conversations you have in life, the
生活中遇到的挑战性对话越多，
higher quality your life is because most
生活质量就越高，因为
of us try to run away as you're saying,
我们大多数人都会像你说的，试图逃避，
right? So, I think there are a couple
对吧？所以，我认为
things that we could do. One is
我们可以做几件事。首先，
sometimes
有时候
you won't be equipped to have that
你可能没有能力进行这样的
conversation or your partner won't be
对话，或者你的伴侣可能没有
equipped to have that conversation.
能力进行这样的对话。
That's the importance of having a third
这就是第三方介入的重要性
party, right? This is the reason why,
，对吧？这就是为什么心理
you know, therapy is so incredibly
咨询如此
important. And I and I and I really try
重要的原因。我真的…… 我之所以想
to preach this because I feel like the
强调这一点，是因为我觉得
UK is a little bit behind the US, you
英国在这方面比美国有点落后。你
know, when it comes to that is therapy
知道，在心理咨询这件事上，美国觉得心理咨询
is sexy. You know, having a counselor is
很性感。你知道，找个咨询师很
sexy. You know what I mean? So having a
性感。你明白我的意思吗？所以，找个
third party, a professional one, that's
第三方，一个专业的咨询师，这
very important.
非常重要。
Secondly is is uh is is context. Picking
其次，是情境。选择
the right moments to have these
合适的时机和
right environments to have these
环境来进行这些棘手的
conversations are incredibly important.
对话至关重要。
Right? You could you could we could
对吧？比如，我们可以
decide that we can have this argument in
决定在
the kitchen when we know that the boys
厨房里讨论这个问题，因为我们知道孩子们
have to be in bed in 5 minutes and I
五分钟后就要睡觉了，而且我知道
know it's been a long day for you and I
你今天很累，我
haven't slept last night. We could have
昨晚也没睡。
this conversation right now if you want
如果你愿意，我们现在就可以谈
to. it's probably not going to go in the
。但谈话可能不会朝着
direction we wanted to. Or we could wait
我们想要的方向发展。或者我们可以等到
and hold on until Saturday when we're
周六，送
the boys off at at their at their at
孩子们上完课回家的时候，我们
their class and we have 10 minutes to
有十分钟时间
sit in the park and talk about this. So
坐在公园里谈谈这件事。所以，
to have the right context is incredibly
选择合适的情境真的非常非常
incredibly important. Third, I think if
重要。第三，我认为如果
if I'm giving top three is to actually
如果让我列出前三点，那就是
set rules and boundaries.
设定规则和界限。
And this does not happen enough in
这一点在
relationships. And I always say that if
恋爱关系中常常被忽略。我总是说，如果
you don't set boundaries, you will take
你不设定界限，即使是出于好意的伴侣，你也会把
them into bullies if you don't set your
他们变成欺凌者
boundaries. So, you have to set your
。所以，你必须
boundaries from the beginning of the
从恋爱之初就设定界限
relationship, but in particular when
，尤其是在进行
you're having these tough conversations.
艰难对话的时候。
And boundaries could be as simple as
界限可以很简单，比如“
we're going to focus on one topic. When
我们只讨论一个话题”。当
you're having an a a a discussion, the
你进行讨论时，
discussion should be about the topic at
讨论应该围绕当前主题展开
hand, right? But setting what those
，对吧？但要提前设定好这些
boundaries are ahead of time because
界限，因为
typically what ends up happening is
通常情况下，
fights become unfair, right? It's
争吵最终会变得不公平，对吧？
healthy to fight, but it's unhealthy to
争吵本身是健康的，但
fight in an unfair manner. So I think th
以不公平的方式争吵是不健康的。所以，我认为这
those are those are three three
三点是我
Jill and myself that we use when we are
和吉尔在进行讨论时使用的技巧
having our discussions.
。接下来，我想
Quick one from our longest standing
快速介绍一下我们最长期的
sponsor here. I I can't tell you over
赞助商。我不能告诉你具体是什么时候，
the last I'd say over the last really
大概是
it's been about two and a half years. It
两年半的时间吧。
was really um post pandemic how much my
疫情之后，我的
health has become such a huge priority
健康真的变得无比重要
in my life. Hule has been probably the
。Hule 可能是
most important partner in my health
我健康之旅中最重要的伙伴，
journey because I've been in the
因为我曾多次
boardrooms. I've been to their offices
拜访他们的办公室，亲眼
times. I've seen how they make their
见证了他们如何制定
decisions on nutrition and I trust it. I
营养决策，并且我非常信任他们。我
trust the brand to keep me nutritionally
相信这个品牌能够让我获得
complete. And that is something that I
全面的营养。
fight for every single day in the chaos
在忙碌
and the busyiness of my life. And that's
而混乱的生活中，我每天都在努力追求这一点。因此，
able to talk to this audience about a
能够和大家分享这个
brand and a product that is so
品牌和产品，对我来说意义非凡。它与
unbelievably linked to my values and the
我的价值观以及
and the place I am in my life of valuing
我目前的生活状态紧密相连，我重视
the gym, exercise, movement, my mind, my
健身、运动、身心健康、
breathing and all of those things and
呼吸以及所有这些，而
most importantly my nutrition. That is
最重要的是，我重视营养。这就是
the role he Hu plays. And so if you
Hule 所扮演的角色。所以，如果你
haven't already tried Hu and you've been
还没试过 Hule，或者一直被
resistant to my my pestering then give
我的推荐所困扰，那就试试吧，然后
it a go and let me know how you get on.
告诉我你的感受。最后，
Quick word from one of my sponsors. Um,
我的赞助商也想说几句。嗯，
super excited to announce that our new
太棒了！ 非常激动地宣布，我们
sponsor for the podcast is Intel, a
播客的新赞助商是英特尔。
brand that pretty much every single
几乎所有
person listening to this is a user of,
听众都是英特尔的用户，
but in some cases you might not even
但有些人可能并不
know. For those that don't know, Intel
了解它。对于那些不了解英特尔的人，它
is a technological powerhouse who have
是一家科技巨头，50多年来一直致力于
been driving technology innovation and
推动技术创新和
transformation for more than 50 years.
变革。
We all know that technology has never
我们都知道，科技的
been more important than it is today.
重要性从未像今天这样突出。
And Intel is truly shaping the future of
英特尔正在真正塑造
our industry. from keeping us connected
我们行业的未来。从通过5G让我们保持连接（
through 5G, which we use in all of our
我们每天都在使用5G），
lives every single day, to modernizing
到实现
computers to transforming businesses
计算机现代化，再到
through data and analytics. The list
通过数据和分析改变企业运营，英特尔的贡献数不胜数
goes on and on and on. I've been
。我
particularly excited to announce this
特别兴奋地宣布这项
sponsorship because we've been using
赞助，因为我们已经在办公楼和播客中使用
Intel's technology throughout this
英特尔的技术
building and on this podcast for some
一段
time now, and it makes our lives so much
时间了，它
easier in so many ways, especially as it
在很多方面都极大地简化了我们的工作，尤其是
relates to producing this show for you.
在制作这档节目方面。
So, head over to intel.co.uk UK and you
所以，请访问intel.co.uk英国网站，
can find out why they've become an
了解为什么英特尔的技术已经成为
essential piece of technology in my
我日常工作中不可或缺的一部分
day-to-day routine. Let me know what you
。欢迎留言告诉我你的
think. At some point, um, you started a
想法。嗯，你 我开了个
YouTube channel
YouTube频道，
and Oprah
然后奥普拉
got in touch.
联系了我。是的，太
Yes.
疯狂了。真的太
It's crazy. It's it's uh it's crazy, but
疯狂了。呃，真的太疯狂了，但
it it is uh you know, so
你知道，
when I decided to launch my matchmaking
当我准备了一年之后决定推出我的婚介
business after I spent a year prepping,
业务时，
I didn't know how to launch it. And it
我不知道该如何启动。当时是
was my wife and my best friend at the
我的妻子和我最好的朋友
time who said, you know, you should
说，你应该
focus on the marketing aspect of this.
专注于营销方面。
You should start a YouTube channel. Now,
你应该开一个YouTube频道。现在
this is
是
200 and
2009年
nine.
。非常非常
early.
早。
Were you born in 2009?
你是2009年出生的吗？
Just about. [laughter]
差不多吧。[笑声]
So you know, so 2009, so YouTube isn't a
所以你知道，2009年的时候，YouTube还不是什么
big It's a thing. It's not as big a
大平台。它不像
thing as it is right now. It's not known
现在这么火。它还不是
as the go-to place to market your new
推广新
company.
公司的首选平台。
Um, but I decided to create a YouTube
嗯，但我决定创建一个
series called the Modern Day Matchmaker.
叫做“现代婚介”的YouTube系列节目。我决定把
And what I decided is I would pump all
所有的
of my money into this thing. And I I
钱都投入到这个项目中。我的
mean, when I look around the studio,
意思是，当我环顾四周…… 工作室，
this is an impressive studio. Um I had
这工作室真不错。嗯，我当时只有
like one out of 10 of these cameras. I
十台摄像机中的一台。
had like one camera, you know, but it
你知道，我只有一台摄像机，但
was me spending $1,000 to $4,000 per
我每分钟的制作成本就要1000到4000美元
production minute, right? So we had a
，对吧？所以我们有个
team. Yeah. Yeah. I know it's crazy.
团队。是啊，是啊。我知道这很疯狂，很
It's ridiculous.
荒谬。
But the reason why is because I thought
但原因在于，我认为
I had a unique point of view. And if I
我有一个独特的视角。如果我
can just push that out into the
能把这个视角推向
marketplace, I could distinguish myself
市场，就能让自己
from the competitors. And I would put
从竞争对手中脱颖而出。我
out this video every week, man, and
每周都会发布一个视频，但根本没人看
nobody would watch it. Nobody. And and I
。真的没人看。我这么
say this and this is not even a joke is
说可不是开玩笑，
every week it would get like 11 or 12
每周
views this video and my mother was
这个视频的点击量也就11、12次，其中9次都是我妈
watching nine of those
看的，
you know and so it was no one was
所以根本没人看。
watching this thing but I thought this
但我认为这
you know for for me to at least create
至少能让我
my brand within the space. Now, it turns
在这个领域建立起自己的品牌。结果，这
out that one of those 11 views was
11次点击中竟然有一次是
Oprah.
奥普拉看的。
But people say like, "Okay, how how did
但人们会问：“
Oprah find you?" You know,
奥普拉是怎么找到你的？” 我知道，
the reason why Oprah was able to find me
奥普拉能找到我的原因
is because a year prior, I was doing
是，一年前我做了
probono
义务
matchmaking services.
婚介服务。
Free work.
免费的工作。
Free work. One of my clients, and I had
免费的工作。我的一个客户，我当时完全
no idea, but one of my clients was a
不知道，是《
writer for O Magazine.
O》杂志的撰稿人。
Year later, she's on Oprah's Jet. Oprah
一年后，她上了奥普拉的私人飞机。奥普拉
says, "I have a concept for a new TV
说：“我有个新电视
show. I'm looking for a fresh voice." My
节目的创意。”  “我正在寻找新鲜的声音。”我的
client in the jet says, "Have you heard
客户在飞机上说：“你听说
of Paul Brunson?" Oprah says, "No, but
过保罗·布伦森吗？”奥普拉说：“没有，
let me see."
让我看看。”我在
YouTube search Paul Brunson
YouTube上搜索“保罗·布伦森”，
save let me start watching. So Oprah was
保存后开始观看。奥普拉当时正在
watching this YouTube series and and you
看一个YouTube系列节目，你
know when I always look at it I say gosh
知道，我每次看这个节目都会想，
to me it is a powerful story because she
这对我来说真是一个震撼人心的故事，因为她
ends up offering me a job to co-host a
最终邀请我和
television show with her on her brand
她一起在她
new network off of this YouTube series
新开的电视台主持一档节目，而这一切都源于这个YouTube系列节目，当时
that no one was watching but Oprah, my
除了奥普拉、我
mother, and like two other people. And I
妈妈和另外两个人之外，几乎没人看。我
say it's a powerful story about quality
说这是一个关于质量
over quantity. You know, I think we live
胜于数量的精彩故事。你知道，我觉得我们生活
in a day and age where, you know, vanity
在一个虚荣指标至上的时代，尤其是那些指标，似乎一切都成了最重要的
everything. You know, it's like I need
。比如，我需要
to have this number of followers, this
有多少粉丝，
number of views. And I get it to a
多少观看量。我在某种程度上理解这一点
certain extent. It is important when
。当
you're monetizing, but ultimately the
你需要盈利时，这些指标确实很重要，但最终，
who that's watching is more important.
谁在看才是最重要的。正是
And it was it was through that that, you
通过
know, that that YouTube series that I I
那个YouTube系列节目，我
got the job. and it and working with
得到了这份工作，以及与……的合作。
Oprah changed my life.
奥普拉改变了我的人生。
metrics um in KPIs in business and
在商业和分析的关键绩效指标（KPI）中，有一种叫做滞后指标的东西，指的是在
that show up later once you've done the
你投入时间和
input once you've done the work. And I
精力之后才会显现出来的指标。
was thinking about that as you were
你刚才说话的时候，我一直在想这个，
speaking because you were doing you were
因为你一直
doing focusing on quality. Now, the
专注于质量。
lagging metric was that you were going
滞后指标就是你
to become on Oprah Winfreyy's show and
会上奥普拉·温弗瑞的节目，
she was going to watch, but you were
她会看你的节目，但你
just planting the seeds of quality and
只是在播下质量的种子。
and like I'm sure that if you'd carried
我相信，如果你
on doing that channel for 15 years, it
继续做那个频道15年，它现在
would have probably had 15 million
可能已经有1500万
subscribers, but but it's it's I always
订阅者了。但我总是把
think about it like seeds. Even with
它比作种子。即使考虑到
even what with what we've done here, if
我们在这里取得的成就，如果
I showed you the graph of the growth of
我给你看DEO的增长图表
the DEO, it's literally this is no
，这绝对不是
exaggeration. I posted on my Twitter the
夸张。我前几天在推特上发的
other day. It's 2 years
。两年来一直保持
flat.
平稳增长。
now, what happens next is it goes like a
接下来会发生什么呢？它会像一条
like a vertical lineup.
垂直线一样向上延伸。
Wow.
哇！
And you never know when or how or
你永远不知道什么时候会发生。 或者
whatever, but those first two years when
不管怎样，但头两年虽然比较
it was flat was when all of those seeds
平淡，却是所有种子播种的时期，也是
you're you're learning your craft. And I
你真正学习技艺的时期。我
think so many people um it's an
认为这对
important for so many people because the
很多人来说都很重要，因为
big metrics always lag behind and things
重要的指标总是滞后，事情总是忽快忽慢
fast.
。
Yes.
是的。
And uh we sometimes can get super
我们有时会非常
impatient about why why hasn't Opra
不耐烦，比如为什么奥普拉还没
called me yet or why don't I have a big
给我打电话？为什么我的
podcast or 10 15 million download? Why
播客还没有爆红，下载量还没有达到1000万或1500万？为什么
don't I have that yet? But you're doing
我还没有达到这些目标？但你
the work now to have that in that quiet
现在正在努力，就是为了在这段平静的
period. And I loved what you said there
时期获得这些。我很喜欢你
about like the quality. Like if you just
刚才说的关于质量的部分。如果你
focus on quality, which is something you
专注于质量，这是
know you can control. Just making
你能控制的，那就把
whatever you're doing now like the best.
现在做的每一件事都做到最好。
Yes.
是的，
You have nothing to worry about. You
你没什么好担心的，你
don't need to worry. You just need
不需要担心，你只需要
patience.
耐心。
Yes. Yes.
是的，是的。
And and I love that when I hear that
我喜欢听到
that story cuz 11 views and one of them
这个故事，因为只有11次观看，其中一次竟然是
[__] Oprah is just
奥普拉打来的。是的，就是这样。 真是令人
Yeah. It's it's it's a mind-blow. It's a
震惊。真的，太令人
it's a mind-blow. And and I think to to
震惊了。而且我觉得，我还要
to even add to what you're saying is I
补充一点，我
think that that's the key of having the
认为这才是拥有
passion because that's I mean that's the
激情的关键，因为这就是你坚持
yeah you keep on keeping on.
下去的原因。
You keep on keeping on cuz cuz otherwise
你坚持下去，否则
the first hurdle you hit you give up,
你遇到的第一个障碍就会放弃，
right?
对吧？你应该放弃，
You and you should because 11 you're
因为你真是
[laughter] [__] stupid. Go get a job.
蠢透了。去找份工作吧。
Do you know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
That's what my father was saying. Can
我父亲就是这么说的。
you imagine? He was like what are you
你能想象吗？他问我：“你在干什么
doing? You just came from investment
？你刚从投资
banking. Like I mean honestly Stephen
银行出来。” 说实话，斯蒂芬，很多
the amount of people who thought I was
人都觉得我
crazy like commit this guy he left
疯了，这家伙离开了
investment banking and he's doing
投资银行，现在在
YouTube videos out of his bedroom and
卧室里做YouTube视频，而且他连房贷都
he's not paying for his mortgage right
还不起，对吧？
his wife my wife liquidated her
他老婆，我老婆，把她的退休金都变现了，
so so we had burned through our money
所以我们把钱都花光了，
she liquidates her retirement fund And
她把她的退休金都变现了，然后
we start using that as capital for the
我们开始用这些钱作为
business. And the capital is being used
创业的资金。这些资金被用来
for a YouTube series that 11 people are
制作一个YouTube系列视频。  11个人在
watching. Like people thought I was
看。好像大家都觉得我
nuts.
疯了似的。就是这样
That's it. I think Steve Jobs said it.
。我想史蒂夫·乔布斯说过。
He said, you know, there's going to
他说，你知道，
become a day when you're doing what
总有一天，当你做着
you're doing where any sane person would
你正在做的事情时，任何一个理智的人都会
give up. And they should give up, but
放弃。他们确实应该放弃，但
you'll see before you. But those that
你眼前的事实和数据摆在那里。而那些
keep going are those that are doing it
坚持下去的人，是因为他们内心深处有着
for that really deep internal reason.
非常深刻的理由。
And like one of the things I know for
我确信的一件事
sure is that no matter what business you
是，无论你创办什么企业
start, unless you're very very lucky,
，除非你非常非常幸运，
exceptionally lucky, you're going to
极其幸运，否则你都会遇到这样的日子。而且对
most people a week, months, sometimes
大多数人来说，这种日子不会只有一天，而是会持续一周、几个月，有时甚至好
multiple years where everything is
几年，所有的一切都在
saying you're an idiot. You should stop.
告诉你，你是个白痴，你应该放弃。
And the only way you grace those hurdles
你能够克服这些障碍的唯一方法，
sometimes because you don't have a plan
有时是因为你没有备选方案。
B. That's a very good way to just keep
这是一种坚持下去的绝佳方式，
on keeping on. but because it's a
因为这是
challenge that you must pursue, right?
你必须面对的挑战，对吧？
Regardless of remuneration or outcome,
无论回报或结果如何，都是如此。
it's for you. And so when I bet on
对你来说。所以当我投资
entrepreneurs, especially when I'm
创业者，尤其是
investing in them, I'm looking for that.
投资他们的时候，我就会寻找这些特质。
I'm like, I because I don't I don't know
我会想，因为我
a ton about the industries, but what I
对行业了解不多，但我对
business and I know your hard days are
商业的本质非常了解，我知道你肯定会遇到困难
coming. How will you respond for that
。你会如何应对这
three years where everything is going
三年
bad, right?
糟糕的局面呢？
Resilience, you know, purpose, all of
韧性、目标感，所有
those sort of key indicators. So Oprah,
这些关键指标。所以，奥普拉，
you end up working with Oprah on her
你最终和她一起主持她的
show.
节目。
I guess I got two questions. First one
我想我有两个问题。第一个问题
is, what did you learn from Oprah
是，你从和奥普拉
working so closely with her?
如此密切的合作中学到了什么？
Well, the first thing I learned was not
嗯，我学到的第一件事就是不要
to call her Oprah.
叫她奥普拉。
Oh, really? [laughter] [__]
哦，真的吗？[笑] 糟糕。
No, no, no, no, no, no. You can call if
不，不，不，不，不，不。如果
you are working
你
for her, she's Miss Winfrey. That was
为她工作，你可以叫她温弗瑞小姐。这是
the first thing I learned. Someone
我学到的第一件事。有人
corrected me very quickly. I was like,
很快就纠正了我。我当时说：
"Oh, no." They said, "No, Miss Winfrey."
“哦，不。”他们说：“不，温弗瑞小姐。”
you know. Uh so that that was the first
你知道的。呃，所以…… 那是第一
thing. But she is everything you can
件事。但她比你
imagine that she is times 100.
想象的还要好一百倍。
about Miss Winfrey, about Oprah is that
温弗瑞小姐，也就是奥普拉，让我感兴趣的地方还在于，
when she would speak, you never knew if
她说话的时候，你永远不知道
she was talking about the event in the
她是在谈论
immediate or if she's giving you some,
眼前的事情，还是在给你一些
you know, life advice. Like I remember
人生建议。我记得我
the the very first scene I shot with her
和她一起拍的第一场戏
was we were in Georgia. So we shot a
是在佐治亚州。我们拍了一个
show called Lovetown USA. I actually did
叫《爱之城美国》（Lovetown USA）的节目。我其实和
two shows with Oprah, but the first one
奥普拉合作过两个节目，第一个
was Lovetown USA. And there's 10,000
就是《爱之城美国》。当时现场有1万名
people in this audience. They're all
观众。他们都
there to see Oprah. There's this massive
来看奥普拉。
light kit on stage. It's big. It's my
舞台上有一套巨大的灯光设备。场面非常壮观。那是我
first big event ever. I've never spoken
第一次参加这么大型的活动。我以前从来没有在
front of 10 people, you know, 10,000
10个人面前讲过话，你知道，1万人
people. And the director comes over and
。导演走过来，说：
he was like, "All right, Paul, get up on
“好了，保罗，上台吧
stage. Hit your mark and introduce
。” 各就各位，介绍
Oprah." I was thinking, "Hit my mark.
奥普拉。” 我当时想的是：“各就各位。”
What is a mark?" Like, "What does that
“什么是印记？”就像，“那是什么
mean?" And I'm freaking out. I'm
意思？”我当时都快疯了，浑身
sweating. And Oprah comes over to me
冒汗。这时奥普拉平静地走到我身边，
real calm, cool. Puts her hand on my on
把手放在我的
my shoulder. She's like, "All right,
肩膀上，说：“好了，
baby. Look, this is it's it's real
宝贝。” 你看，这很
simple. You just walk on that stage.
简单。 你只要走上那个舞台就行了。
Keep walking till you feel the light hit
一直走，直到你感觉阳光最强
you the brightest.
地照在你身上。   “
That's where you stay, right?" And I was
你就住在那儿，对吧？”我当时就在
thinking to myself, is she talking about
想，她是在说
the stage? Is she talking about life?
舞台吗？还是在说人生？（
Like, [laughter] because that's deep,
笑）因为这很深刻，
you know? But that's how she would
你知道吗？但她就是这么
speak. Um, and she was uh she she just
说话的。嗯，她……她……她简直
just amazing. Just just amazing,
太棒了。真的太棒了，
amazing, amazing person.
太棒了，太棒了。
Why is she successful in your
为什么你觉得她成功
assessment? Why is she Oprah? Oprah,
？为什么她是奥普拉？奥普拉，
what is it about her?
她到底有什么特别之处？是
Yeah. So, so I I studied her, you know,
啊。所以，我研究过她，你知道，
I'm a people watcher, you know, uh, and
我喜欢观察人，你知道，嗯，
I worked for, so I worked for Oprah
我
after I worked for Enver. And the
之前为恩维尔工作，之后又为奥普拉工作。
similarity to me is that when I started
我觉得相似之处在于，我开始
working for Enver, he went from
为恩维尔工作时，他从
multi-millionaire to billionaire. And
千万富翁变成了亿万富翁。
that to me was was really interesting
这对我来说真的很有意思，
because of how few billionaires, you
因为世界上亿万富翁很少
know, there are in in in the world. So I
。所以我
started to journal what I learned from
开始记录我从
Enver. Then I started working for Oprah
恩维尔身上学到的东西。然后我开始为奥普拉工作，
and I noticed similarities and what was
我注意到了一些相似之处，让
wild to me is here are two people who
我感到惊讶的是，这两个人
are completely different. You know, one
完全不同。你知道，一个 一个
woman, one man, one from the US, one
女人，一个男人，一个美国人，一个
Turkey. One married, one not. One
土耳其人。一个已婚，一个未婚。一个
Christian, one Muslim. It's like
基督徒，一个穆斯林。他们看似
completely different, but yet they have
截然不同，却又有着
these same characteristics. And for
相同的特质。尤其是
Oprah in particular, you know, I noticed
奥普拉，你知道，我注意到
we used to go on these road shows for
我们以前会为她的节目做巡回宣传，
the show to sell the show to to
向
advertisers. And before the road show,
广告商推销节目。在巡回宣传之前，
she would also she would always host a
她总是会举办
dinner. And these dinners, there would
晚宴。这些晚宴通常
be, you know, 20 30 people at the
会有二三十人参加
dinner. You'd have all types of athletes
。你会看到各种各样的运动员
and politicians and uh you know she
、政客，她还会
would have her she would bring her some
邀请她
of her girls from her school in South
在南非学校的一些学生来参加
Africa would also be at the table. It
。那就像一个热闹
would be this poperri, this eclectic
非凡的
buffet of various people and she would
盛宴，形形色色的人齐聚一堂，她
sit and she would conduct these these
坐在那里主持着这些
amazing dinners. And I realized that at
精彩的晚宴。我意识到，在
these dinners that was her education was
这些晚宴上，
was the dinner like she was being
她就像是在学习，了解
world, what's going to happen tomorrow,
世界上正在发生的事情，以及未来将会发生什么，
right? Because she had a lot of the
对吧？因为她邀请了很多
playmakers at the table. She was
有影响力的人参加。她从中
learning about different perspectives.
了解了不同的观点。
She was teasing out her own ideas and
她会在把想法
debating them before she would take them
搬上荧幕之前，反复琢磨、反复辩论。
on screen. She would do this in these
她会在
intimate dinner settings. And I noticed
私密的晚餐场合这样做。我注意到
Enver would do the same thing. Massive
恩维尔也会这样做。他
dinners, 20, 30 people every night. He
每晚都会举办大型晚宴，招待二三十人。他
would have these massive dinners and he
也会举办这种大型晚宴，而且他
would do the same thing. They they they
也会做同样的事情。他们，
would they would, you know, they they
你知道，他们的
the concept is never eat alone. You
理念是“永远不要独自用餐”。你
know, Keith Farazzi has a book called
知道，基思·法拉齐写了一本书叫《
Never Eat Alone, which I think is a
永远不要独自用餐》，我觉得这
phenomenal book, but it's about the
本书非常棒，它讲述了
power of socializing and the power that
社交的力量，以及通过
strengthening your the weak ties in your
加强你人际网络中的弱关系所获得的力量。很
Interesting. I think I'm quite bad at
有意思。我觉得我不太擅长
socializing.
社交。
you you you know
你知道，
so I was going to say I'm wondering if
所以我想说，我想知道是否有
there's like a digital equivalent or if
类似的数字化方式，或者
like I'm doing it right now.
我现在正在做的就是社交。
Yes. See I think this this is your
是的。你看，我认为这是你的
extension but so okay so let's let's
延伸，所以，好的，让我们再深入探讨一下
even tease this out a little bit. So
。
Mark Granaveter who was a Stanford
斯坦福大学的教授马克·格拉纳维特
professor came up with this theory of of
提出了
weak ties right. So if you take Robin
弱关系理论，对吧？ 所以，以罗宾·
Dunar, right, who has the Dunar rule, we
杜纳尔为例，她提出了杜纳尔法则，我们
have roughly 150 friends essentially,
大概有150个朋友，
right? You could debate it out, but on
对吧？你可以对此进行辩论，但
average, right?
平均而言，对吧？
Um, if you think about your 150th
嗯，想想你的第150个
friend, the weakest
朋友，那些关系最弱的
friends, right? The 140th friend, right?
朋友，对吧？第140个朋友，对吧？
Acquaintance.
泛泛之交。
Acquaintance, right?
泛泛之交，对吧？
Those are where our biggest
我们
in life come.
人生中最大的机遇就来自这些人。
That's where deals come for our
我们的
business. That's where we get introduced
生意机会来自他们。我们认识
to spouses, right? That's where,
伴侣的机会来自他们，对吧？
you know, tickets to the football game
你知道，足球比赛的门票也
come. It comes from the weakest ties
来自他们。这些机会来自最弱的关系，而不是
opposed to our nearest and dearest,
我们最亲近的人。
which you think about, you think, God,
你可能会想，天哪，这合乎
is that even logical? But it is. Our
逻辑吗？但事实的确如此。我们
weakest ties drive the most opportunity
最弱的关系为我们带来最多的机会
in our life. But what do we do? Most of
。但我们做了什么呢？
us we spend all of our time where with
我们大多数人把所有时间都花在了
the people closest to us. But what Oprah
最亲近的人身上。但奥普拉
and Enenver do and what Mark Granaveter
和埃内维尔所做的，以及马克·格拉纳维特在
talks about with this theory is that the
这个理论中提到的，
key is to constantly be strengthening
关键在于不断加强
our weak ties, investing in those weak
我们的弱关系，投资于这些弱
ties, adding new people in to our weak
关系，增加…… 新人挤进我们原本就脆弱的
ties, kicking other other people out.
关系网，把其他人踢出去。
And that's what they're they're doing.
他们就是这么做的。
Those people at that table, those were
桌上那些人，
not her besties. Those were not her top
不是她最好的朋友，也不是她最重要的
five, right? Those were her 120th,
五个人，对吧？他们是她第120个、
130th. And that's where enormous
130个朋友。而这正是巨大
opportunity comes in.
机遇的来源。
Interesting. So, your matchmaking
有意思。所以，
business becomes, from what I read, one
据我所知，你的婚介公司后来发展成为美国
of the largest matchmaking companies in
最大的婚介公司之一
the United States.
。
Yes.
是的。
How long did that take? The the Paul C.
这花了多长时间？保罗·C·
Brunson Agency.
布伦森婚介公司。
Oh my god. That was 2000. So, that was
我的天哪。那是2000年。所以，那是从
to 2016. So, eight years.
到2016年。八年。在你接触过的
Who of all the the avatars of the sort
所有这类
of personas
人物中，
do you find struggles with being alone
你觉得谁最难以忍受孤独
the most?
？
Oh my. You know what? Men
哦，我的天。你知道吗？是男人吗
Yeah. And I would even say uh you know I
是的。我甚至可以说，你
mean you know there's a whole incel
知道，现在有一个“非自愿独身者”（incel）
movement,
运动，
right? Uh but but and you know there's
对吧？嗯，但是，你知道，
lots of articles now about the the rise
现在有很多文章都在讨论
of of the lonely man you know uh but
孤独男性的兴起，你知道，嗯，但是 说
quite honestly
实话，
what or at least from experience and
至少根据我的经验，要
remember this is 2016 slightly you know
知道现在是2016年，
slightly different time but successful
时代略有不同，但成功
men and I when I say financially
人士——我指的是经济上的
successful so those who were the
成功人士——比如那些
45 years old retired from investment
45岁就从投资
banking, thinking about their next
银行退休，正在考虑下一份
career, divorced twice,
职业，离过两次婚，
sitting at home alone,
独自在家的人，
right?
对吧？
That's where the struggle, that's where
这就是挣扎所在，这就是痛苦的根源所在。
it hits you, you know, when you realize,
你知道，当你意识到，
oh my god, I'm 45. I I'm I'm I've only
天哪，我45岁了。我才
lived half my life, you know, and here I
活了一半的人生，而我却
am alone and I'm a dick on top of it.
孤身一人，而且还是个混蛋。
Right? So that's that was that was the
对吧？所以，这就是
demo. That was there was a struggle.
目标人群。这就是他们面临的困境。
I got to be honest, when I asked you
说实话，当我问你
that question about which group of
哪个群体
people would struggle the most with
最容易感到
loneliness, my head bounced around. I
孤独时，我脑子里一片混乱。
thought I think he's going to say
我想他可能会说是
potentially um younger men because of
年轻男性，因为现在有“非自愿独身者”（
this whole incel thing where you know I
incel）这种现象，你知道，我
don't want to get into the mass
不想讨论大规模
shootings and stuff but kid you know
枪击之类的事件，但是年轻人，你知道，那些……
young men who have I had a guest on this
我之前有一位嘉宾 在这个
podcast Scott Galloway who talked about
播客里，斯科特·加洛韦（Scott Galloway）谈到，
90% of the female attention even when
即使考虑到像Bumble这样的约会软件，90%的女性关注度仍然会流向
to like the top five 10% of men.
排名前10%的男性。
Yes.
是的。
And then you've got this kind of the
然后
other 40% do okay. Then you got the
剩下的40%男性表现尚可。最后还有
bottom 50% of men that are totally just
50%的男性，他们完全
not getting that haven't been laid for
得不到任何关注，有些人甚至
for more than a year. I think that's
一年多都没性生活了。我想他是这么
what he said. Um, so I thought maybe
说的。嗯，所以我以为
you'd go for them. Then I thought he's
你会选择这部分人群。然后我又觉得他会
going to say
提到
30 plus women
30岁以上的女性，
because of things like biological clocks
因为她们会受到生物钟之类的因素影响
and stuff like that,
，
right? Um, and this sort of social
对吧？嗯，还有那种社会
pressure which I I I've heard from
压力，我从其他
guests here that some women can feel
嘉宾那里也听到过，有些女性会感受到
because of society's expectations and
来自社会期望和
timelines to like to hurry up and be
时间限制的压力，比如被催促着赶紧
married. So, I thought you would say one
结婚。所以，我以为你会提到
of those two groups. So, to hear you say
这两类人群中的一类。所以，听到你说的是
a completely different group
完全不同的群体，是的，这确实让我
Yeah.
很惊讶。是的
Yeah. No, I hear you. And and and what
，我明白你的意思。
you just said that's a logical it's a
你刚才说的这个
logical breakout. But for me and this is
划分很合乎逻辑。 对我来说，这是
my experiences dealing with those who
我与那些
are seeking matchmaking you know is that
寻求婚介的人打交道的经验，你知道，他们
the thought is
常常会想“
my time is over you know my my the the
我的时代已经过去了”，你知道，我的
heyday is gone you know it's kind of
黄金时代已经结束了，你知道，这有点像一个退役的
like the the athlete that is now retired
运动员，他
but want but still desires to play but
仍然渴望比赛，但他
realizes that they don't have you know
意识到自己已经
they don't have it anymore. But a rich
没有那个实力了。但是一个
40 40-y old man
40岁的富裕男人，
Yes.
是的，他
has got options.
有很多选择。
Has you know what? A rich 40 Yeah. H has
你知道吗？一个40岁的富裕男人，是的，他有很多
options. But but we're talking about
选择。但是，我们现在要谈的是
loneliness though.
孤独。
Okay. Right.
好吧。对。
Loneliness. Yeah.
孤独。是的。
over you when you realize, you know, so
当你意识到这一点时，一种空虚感就会袭来，你知道，所以，
a large part of loneliness unfortunately
不幸的是，孤独很大程度上来自于
is through comparison. Because you know
比较。因为你知道，
this whole idea when we compare we
当我们比较时，我们会感到
despair. We despair upon oursel. So, a
绝望。我们会对自己感到绝望。所以，
large part of that is is that you look
很大一部分原因是，当你
across your peers and you say, "Look at
看着你的同龄人，你会说：“看看
this. Now, Steven's married, you know,
这个。” 现在，史蒂文结婚了，你知道，
he's two children, you know, and I'm
他有两个孩子，你知道，而我，
yeah, I'm out here. I have my Ferrari,
嗯，我在这里。 我有一辆法拉利，
you know, but I come home to myself
你知道，但我回到家，回到我的
in my big house
大房子里，回到我那
in my big in my massive house. And
巨大的房子里，回到我自己的世界。 这里一个人也没有，我身边空无一人
with me. And you're astute enough to
。 你足够敏锐，
know that all of those people who you
知道所有那些你
thought were loyal to you were actually
以为对你忠诚的人，实际上
not loyal to you, but they were just
并不忠于你，他们只是
loyal to their circumstances with you
忠于你
and the job and stuff. Yeah. Yeah.
和这份工作之间的关系而已。 是的。 是的。
The job, right? Ex. Exactly. So you So
那份工作，对吧？ 前任。 确切地。 所以
you begin to understand, oh my god,
你开始明白，哦我的天哪，
they're not my friends. I I have I I I
他们不是我的朋友。 我没有任何
have no one. And so when you have
人。 所以，当
someone to go to a matchmaker, typically
有人去找媒人时，通常意味着
they have reached the end of their line
他们在寻找伴侣这件事上已经走投无路了，
you know, and I think that
你知道，而且我认为，
from my peers who are of that age or
在我同龄的同辈人中，或者
I'll say of that vintage, right? Um that
说同龄人中，情况也是如此，对吧？ 嗯，
it is uh you know it's it's it's
你知道，这真是太
incredibly sad. It it's just it's just
令人难过了。 这真是太
incredibly sad. Now, I think what women
令人难过了。 我认为，女性
do tremendously well, or should I say
做得非常出色的一点，或者应该说
better than men of that age, is they
比同龄男性做得更好的一点，是她们
understand how to build community.
懂得如何建立社群。
And that's something that goes back to
而这又回到了
what we were talking about before, the
我们之前讨论的内容，
we talked about, you know, the feedback
我们之前讨论过的反馈
loop. We talked about uh you know
循环。 我们讨论了在
challenges around being emotionally
情感上保持
available especially at an early age
开放所面临的挑战，尤其是在年幼时
understanding how to build emotional
理解如何建立情感
intimacy.
亲密关系。
The these these things all play
这些事情
themselves out not only in our romantic
不仅会在我们的恋爱
relationships but in our platonic
关系中体现出来，也会在我们的友谊
relationships. And what we have to
关系中体现出来。 我们必须
understand is that the the stronger
明白的是，
platonic relationships we have,
我们拥有的柏拉图式关系越牢固，
the more health we have, the longer we
我们的身体就越健康，寿命就越长
live, the more money you you know we we
，我们赚的钱也就越多
make. You know, I have a so I have a
。 你知道，我有一个，所以我有一个，她
it's my wife's u aunt. She is 111 years
是我妻子的姑姑。 她今年111
old.
岁了。
Jesus.
耶稣。
So she's one of the oldest human beings
所以她是
right now on the planet. She's 111,
目前地球上最年长的人类之一。 她111岁了，
incredibly astute. And when I sit down,
非常精明。 当我坐下来的时候，
I just sit down and I'm just I absorb
我就只是坐下来，把
everything that she says. And what I
她说的每一句话都吸收进去。 我
realiz is she still has friends. Like at
意识到她仍然有朋友。 就像
111.
111岁那年一样。
She has friends that she talks to every
她每天都和朋友们聊天
day. You know, that's how you stay
。 你知道，那样才能
alive. You know, we we focus and I get
活下去。 你知道，我们专注于此，我明白了
it. You know, gut health is so important
。 你知道，肠道健康
and low cholesterol is so important.
和低胆固醇都非常重要。   是的
Yeah. I I I get it. Right. Exercise is
。 我明白了。 正确的。 运动真的
so important, right? I get all those
非常重要，对吧？ 我知道所有这些
things are so important, but I would
都很重要，但我
argue that our social connections are
认为我们的社交关系
even more important and we have to
更重要，我们必须
understand how to build the skills and
懂得如何培养这些技能，而且
you do that before, like I always say,
就像我常说的，
the best time to work on your marriage
经营婚姻的最佳时间
is before you get married. You know, the
就是在结婚之前。 你知道，在
before you have your friend, right? We
拥有朋友之前培养友谊是最佳时机，对吧？ 我们
need to develop these skills early on.
需要尽早培养这些技能。
Someone said to me in fact yesterday so
事实上，昨天有人跟我说，这跟
it rings so true to what you're saying
你说的很吻合。
that um we were talking about resilience
我们当时在讨论韧性，
and they said we used to think of
他们说我们过去认为
resilience as like being tough yourself
韧性就是自己坚强，
but when when we look at different
但当我们观察不同的
people the resilience comes from being
人时，会发现韧性来自于被
surrounded by commu a supportive
支持性的
community and that in fact makes a
社群所包围，这实际上使一个
person an individual resilient
人在
psychologically resilient so when I
心理上具有韧性。所以，当我
think about that investment banker
想到那位
that's 45 years old and alone he doesn't
45岁、孤身一人的投资银行家时，他
have a community to help keep his
没有社群来帮助他保持
psychological resilience in place. And
心理韧性。
interesting study that I that I read
我读过一篇非常有趣的研究，
about um and this goes back to our sort
它追溯到我们的
of ancestorial
祖先
backgrounds where we lived together in
背景，那时我们生活在
these tight-knit communities where if
紧密联系的社区里。
someone the reason why when people are
人们感到
lonely they they live less long and
孤独时寿命更短，
they're more susceptible to illness,
更容易生病，
disease, and all of these other things
以及其他各种问题，这
is because scientists have seen that the
是因为科学家发现，
brain literally goes into a state called
大脑会进入一种叫做
self-preservation
自我保护的状态，比如在
where your sleep. So think about it. If
睡眠中。 所以好好想想。 如果
you left your tribe and you're out on
你离开了你的部落，来到了
the I don't know the Serengeti when we
我不知道的塞伦盖蒂，那时我们已经生活在
were I don't know tens of thousands of
几万
years ago or whatever everything's ch
年前了，或者不管怎样，
everything changes in terms of your your
一切都会改变，你的
keeping yourself alive. You can't sleep
生存方式也会随之改变。 你再也睡不好觉了
the same. So they observe the brain of
。 所以他们观察孤独者的大脑，这些人
someone who's lonely and they struggle
难以
with sleep because we've been programmed
入睡，因为我们被设定
to [__] stay up cuz the lion might be
为要熬夜，因为狮子可能会
coming. And this is really interesting.
来。 这真有意思。
brain now because I started learning
现在我脑子里所有这些点都连起来了，因为我开始学习一种
about this thing called chronotypes
叫做“生物钟类型”的东西，
people what you'll find is they all have
你会发现，在一个20到30人的群体中，每个人的
completely different sleeping rhythms
睡眠节律、
when they get hungry when they're most
饥饿时间、
creative when they have the most power.
创造力最强的时间以及精力最充沛的时间都完全不同。
So I'm an owl. My my my partner was was
我是一只猫头鹰。 我的伴侣则
the opposite.
恰恰相反。
And the reason why we have the different
而我们之所以会有不同的
chronotypes again it goes back to the
生物钟类型，可以追溯到
tribal days where like we didn't all
部落时代，那时我们并不
want to sleep at the same time or be
想在同一时间睡觉或保持
alert at the same time. So we create a
清醒。 所以我们建立了一个
community where we're basically one
社区，在这个社区里，我们基本上是部落
shield of the tribe to survive. And
生存的一面盾牌。
thinking about that guy who's 45 years
想想那个45岁的人
old, he's got the bag, but he's lonely
，他很有钱，但却孤独得
as [__] He's in self-preservation.
要命。 他这是在自保。
Yeah, that's a great point.
没错，你说得很有道理。
You know, physiologically, your brain is
你知道，从生理角度来说，当你陷入孤独状态时，你的大脑会
completely different uh when you fall
完全不同，
into a state of loneliness and because
因为
your body's trying to help you survive
你的身体会试图帮助你
in this danger, potentially dangerous
在这个充满危险、潜在危险的
world from the lions out there.
世界中生存下来，比如面对狮子的威胁。   是的
Yeah. The other thing they noticed was
。 他们还注意到，
when someone was lonely is their levels
当一个人感到孤独时，他们的
of resentment. Like the snappiness, the
怨恨程度也会增加。 比如易怒、
like anger, the all of that went up as
暴躁等等，这些情绪也都上升了
well. And that links to what you said
。 这和你之前说的
about they don't learn the skills to to
他们不学习
form connections cuz they've got so used
建立人际关系的技能有关，因为他们太习惯于
to self-defense, like psychological
自我保护，比如心理上的
self-defense.
自我保护。   是的
Yeah. Yeah. And I can see that if you're
。 是的。 而且我可以看出，如果你
in that state, then you just delve
处于那种状态，那么随着时间的推移，你就会越陷越深，就像
as each year go like you become a
你变成了一个
kromagin. Like you become Yeah.
克罗马金人一样。 就像你变成了“是的”。   是的
Yeah. Recluse. It's just it's that that
。 隐士。 只是
to me is sad because you have someone
我觉得这很令人难过，因为你觉得
who you p you perceive them to have it
你认识的人似乎拥有
all.
一切。   是的
Yeah.
。
But they really have nothing.
但他们真的什么都没有。
And it makes sense because if I was if I
这很有道理，因为如果我
got used to being alone, say I was on
习惯了独处，比如说我在……
the in the I don't know, I don't even
我不知道，我甚至不
know where prehistoric humans used to
知道史前人类曾经
live. Just in the savannah of Africa.
居住在哪里。 就在非洲大草原上。
[laughter] I just put us there because
[笑声] 我把我们放在那里只是因为
we're all from Africa,
我们都来自非洲，
right? And I've got so used to living
对吧？ 我已经习惯了
alone, when I see someone else or a
独居，所以当我看到其他人或一群
tribe, I'm not going to run up like,
人时，我不会像以前那样跑过去说：
"Hey, I'm going [laughter] to think
“嘿，我要躲起来了（笑），我觉得
these [__] are going to kill me.
这些混蛋会杀了我。
I'm going to hide."
我要躲起来。”   是的
Yeah. Trust goes down. You're you're
。 信任度下降。 你很
you're apprehensive.
焦虑。
You know, all of those things that you
你知道，你
actually described early on,
之前描述的那些事情，确实会
that happens. And that makes perfect
发生。 这完全
sense.
合情合理。   是的
Yeah. Yeah.
。 是的。   那
What do you do though? So, in that case
你具体是做什么的呢？ 所以，对于
of that investment banker, what is step
那位投资银行家来说，第一步是什么，
one to get them from that point where
才能让他从坐在
they're on the couch, they've got all
沙发上、拥有
that money in that mansion, they're
豪宅里所有财富、
alone. how to get them out there and
孤身一人的境地，走向成功呢？ 如何让他们走出舒适圈，
find someone to love them.
找到爱他们的人。   是的
Yeah. I mean therapy you you know with
。 我的意思是，你知道，治疗和
so with matchmaking one of the things
婚介是
that we introduced we we were pioneers
我们引入的一项技术，我们
in many ways. One way is that you would
在很多方面都是先驱。 一种方法是你
come to us and we wouldn't just simply
来找我们，我们不会直接帮
find dates for you. We you would come to
你找约会对象。 你来找
us and then we would assign you to a
我们，然后我们会给你安排一位
therapist that you'd work with for 3 to
治疗师，在你约会之前，你会和他/她一起进行 3 到
six months before you went on your date.
6 个月的治疗。
Right? So there's this rehabilitation,
正确的？ 所以，
you know, that takes place and and what
你知道，康复治疗是一个过程，而
I always say about therapy too is it's
我一直以来对治疗的看法是，这
not you go to a therapist and you're
并不是说你去看了治疗师，然后你就
fixed, you know, it's you begin to build
痊愈了，而是你要开始锻炼
the muscle and you continue that, right?
肌肉，然后坚持下去，对吧？
So that would be a place to begin.
所以，这或许是一个不错的起点。
Secondly is to begin friendships is
其次，
where I would go. So it's not like okay
我会去结交朋友。 所以，这并不是说，好吧，
how can I place you in a community of 10
我该如何把你安排到一个由10
people but how can I find one person
个人组成的群体中，而是我该如何找到一个
that you could begin to build a
你可以开始建立
relationship with and start with
关系的人，从
building rapport you know very basic
建立融洽的关系开始，你知道，非常基础，
very you know very very basic very slow
非常非常基础，非常缓慢，
but that's how I would begin you you
但这就是我会开始的方式。你
know also talking about that particular
知道，还要谈谈那位
client because you know it's it's been
客户，因为你知道，
some while since I've been matchmaking
我已经有一段时间没有做婚介了，
but now he's coming back to me um
但现在他又回来找我了。
very you know what I found with men of
你知道，我发现
that particular vintage, right, in the
那个年龄段的男士在
dating scene is is that the a lot of the
约会方面，很多
the body movements were were I would
肢体语言我都会觉得很
call odd, right? The there was a social
奇怪，对吧？ 你知道，当时存在一种社交上的
ineptness,
笨拙，
you know, um that needed to be worked
嗯，需要加以
out, you know, body like we we say more
解决，你知道，就像我们
with our body than than we do with our
用身体表达的比用
words. And there was a
语言表达的更多一样。
you know, that took months to to tease
你知道，那种不适感花了几个月的时间才慢慢
out. And this is especially if you are
消散。 如果你之前从事的是需要身居
authority, you are the boss, you're
要职、担任领导、是行业
you're you're the top dog. So you don't
领头羊的职业，那就更是如此了。 所以你觉得
no one is critiquing your body language,
没有人会批评你的肢体语言，
right? But now you move to a social
对吧？ 但现在你进入了一个社交
situation where your entire interaction
场合，在这个场合中，你的所有互动
is largely based on your body language.
很大程度上都依赖于你的肢体语言。
It's it's it's a different situation. So
这是另一种情况。 所以
it takes it takes months, right? Or it
需要几个月的时间，对吧？ 或者
could take years, but it takes a while
可能需要数年时间，但在此
of work before, you know, before we we
之前，你知道，在我们
begin the matchmaking.
开始牵线搭桥之前，需要一段时间的准备工作。
I'm like slowly developing a theory on
我正在慢慢地构建一个关于
awkward huggers. [laughter] Do
尴尬拥抱者的理论。  [笑声]
you know what I mean? Those people that
你明白我的意思吗？ 那些人，
They look away when they come in to hug
当他们进来拥抱你时，会把目光移开
you. They kind of give you a tap on the
。 他们就像轻轻拍了拍你的背，让你惊呼“
back of
我的天哪”。   是的
Yeah.
。
Can I Okay. Can we talk about hugging
我可以吗？好的。 我们能稍微聊聊拥抱吗
for a second?
？
100%.
100%。
I noticed that men do this. So So I have
我注意到男人也会这样做。 我有
a buddy named Tom Reed Wilson who's on
个朋友叫汤姆·里德·威尔逊，他和
one of the shows with me and he taught
我一起主持一个节目，他教了
me something that I now pay close
我一些东西，我现在非常
attention to. So most men I notice hug
注意这些事情。 我注意到大多数男人都会拥抱
and tap the back.
并轻拍背部。   滚开！
Get the [__] off me. [laughter]
[笑声]
It's like right. But what Tom taught me
没错。 但汤姆教会我的
is the hold and embrace.
是拥抱和接纳。
And hold and embrace for 30 seconds,
拥抱并保持30秒，
which is a long freaking time to embrace
这对于拥抱
someone.
一个人来说可是相当长的时间。
Wow.
哇。
And what he taught me was that in that
他教会我的是，在
embrace to notice how uncomfortable the
拥抱对方时，要留意
person is with you. There's a okay, you
对方对你有多不自在。 好吧，你
going to let me go? Is this is odd? Now,
会放我走吗？ 这很奇怪吗？ 现在，
this is not to a stranger, but this is
这不是对陌生人，而是对
this is someone who you would hug
你想拥抱的人，而
opposed to the pat is is is the hug.
不是轻拍的拥抱。
That to me is wild. But here's here's
我觉得这太不可思议了。 但这里还有
another wild one that men do. This I
男人会做的另一种疯狂事。 我
learned this from Robin Dunar also in
从 Robin Dunar 的
his book Friendship
著作《友谊
is and and if you see two men talking to
是》中也学到了这一点。如果你看到两个男人
each other at a party out on the street,
在街上的聚会上交谈，
they normally stand at at like a 120°
他们通常会以大约 120° 的
angle. Rarely do they stand like this.
角度站立。 他们很少这样站着。
Never would they stare like this because
他们绝不会这样盯着我们看，因为我们又回到了
going back to us on the Serengeti,
塞伦盖蒂，
right? This is very confrontational,
对吧？ 这很有对抗性，
right? This means we're about to kill
对吧？ 这意味着我们马上就要
each other, [laughter] you know? But
互相残杀了，[笑声] 你知道吗？ 但这样一来
like this,
，
we're safe. You know, if we cheat our
我们就安全了。 你知道，如果我们这样欺骗自己的
bodies like this, the 123 and and if you
身体，123，而且如果你
notice that, men do that all the time.
注意到这一点，男人总是这样做。
Now, ladies walk right up beyond the
现在，女士们径直走到
[laughter]
[笑声]
How you doing, girl? You know, but men,
你好吗，姑娘？ 你知道，但是男人嘛，
it's like, okay, I'm going to talk.
就好像，好吧，我要开始说话了。
You're right. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
你说得对。 是的。 是的。 是的。   是的
Yeah. [clears throat] Yeah. Don't hug
。  [清嗓子] 是的。 不要抱
me. [laughter]
我。  [笑声] 是的
Yeah.
。   是的
Yeah. So, but but but the the these see
。 所以，但是，但是，但是，
these are all things that we we laugh
这些都是我们笑谈
and we joke about, but it suggests why
和开玩笑的事情，但这却揭示了为什么
we could have challenges in our intimate
我们在亲密关系中可能会遇到挑战
relationships.
。
One of the things I've been curious
我一直很好奇，也
about that I have a lot of question
有很多疑问的事情，那就是
compatibility
兼容性
and who who we're compatible with. Are
以及我们和谁兼容。
we just, you know, because when we think
我们是不是只是，你知道，因为当我们想到
about dating, we often think about it
约会时，我们常常会想，我们是不是在
like we're trying to find this perfect
试图找到一个完美的
individual that we could kind of draw on
人，我们可以把这个人画在
a piece of paper that has all of these
一张纸上，上面有所有这些
particular qualities. We think we know
特定的品质。 我们认为我们知道我们
who we're looking for. Um, is that true?
要找的人是谁。 嗯，这是真的吗？
What What do I need to know about like
我需要了解哪些方面才能
what truly makes someone compatible? Cuz
真正判断一个人是否适合我？ 因为
I think once upon a time, for sure, for
我觉得曾经，
sure, I would have said, "I want my
我肯定说过，“我希望我的
partner to be probably like me."
伴侣可能和我一样。”
Right.
正确的。
I would have said, "Fucking [laughter]
我当时会说：“真他妈的[笑]
run a huge business so we can talk about
经营着一家大公司，这样我们就可以
it in bedtime." And
在睡前谈论它了。”
Right.
没错。
that I don't think that's the case
我觉得情况已经不是那样了
[laughter]
[笑声]
anymore. [clears throat]
。  [清嗓子] 是的
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, my my my joke is
。 是的。 我的意思是，我的笑话是，
that most men who came to us, right,
来找我们的大多数男人，对吧，
they want themselves with a vagina.
他们都想要一个阴道。
[laughter]
[笑声]
That's pretty much that's pretty much
这差不多就是
what they're looking for, right? Um, so,
他们想要的，对吧？ 嗯，
uh, this is a topic that's, you know,
这个话题
I've been studying forever and there's a
我一直在研究，而且
lot of different thoughts around it.
围绕它有很多不同的看法。
Like if you just think about dating
比如想想约会
apps, they spend an enormous amount of
软件，他们花费巨资
money trying to perfect the algorithm
来完善算法
to, you know, the matching algorithm,
，你知道，就是匹配算法，一切都围绕着
it's all about that. And if you look at
这个。 如果你看一下
the success rate, so the percentage of
成功率，也就是
people who are using dating apps and
使用约会软件的人
then end up in a committed or committed
最终建立一段稳定的恋爱
relationship or marriage and then stay
关系或婚姻，并且维持
in that for a fixed amount of time, like
这段关系一段固定的时间（比如
10 years, it's like less than 2%. So you
10 年）的比例，就会发现这个比例不到 2%。 所以你会
think, okay, so they haven't gotten it
想，好吧，看来他们没做
right. There's certain matchmakers that
对。 有些婚介机构
profess to have almost near 100% success
声称他们的撮合成功率接近100%
rates. You say, what do they do? You
。 你说，他们是做什么的？ 你
know, I have some friends who just say,
知道吗，我有些朋友会说，
I can just look at you and tell. And
我只要看一眼就能看出来。 然后
you're like, whatever. like you know but
你就想，随便吧。 你知道，
over time there are certain areas that I
随着时间的推移，我坚信某些方面能够
firmly believe firmly believe determine
决定
whether or not you have strong
你们是否具有很强的
compatibility right so one we've already
契合度，对吧？首先，我们已经
talked about attachment style yeah
讨论过依恋类型，是的，
I think attachment style incredibly
我认为依恋类型非常
important we've talked about values
重要，我们也讨论过价值观，
values incredibly important that's the
价值观非常重要，那是
rulebook to life right another part of
人生的准则，对吧？另一个方面
it is your ability to communicate
是你的沟通能力。
So there's this theory called decide
所以有一种理论叫做“决定与
verse slide, right? It's a theory that a
滑动”，对吧？ 这是一种理论，很多人都支持，
people like John Cotman's behind this,
比如约翰·科特曼（John Cotman）等人就支持这种理论，
but you have people in the states who
但在美国，也有人
have looked at when you're with your
研究过，当你和你的
partner, can you make a decision
伴侣在一起时，你们能否
together on anything? Let's say you're
在任何事情上共同做出决定？ 假设你
with your partner and you decide, okay,
和你的伴侣决定，好吧，
we're going on vacation. Can you
我们要去度假。 你们真的能在
going without killing each other? Like,
不互相残杀的情况下决定去哪里吗？ 比如说，
can you decide what you're going to eat
你们能不能在
without killing each other? Like, can
不互相残杀的情况下决定吃什么？ 比如，
you actually make collaborative
你们真的能进行协作
decisions? That is deciding versus
决策吗？ 这是决断还是
sliding. What a lot of relationships,
拖延。 很多情侣，
what a lot of couples do is they say,
很多伴侣都会说：
"Okay, no, you you decide that. You you
“好吧，不，你来决定。你来
pick where we're going to go. I'll
选我们要去哪里。我来
decide where we're going to do." Right?
决定我们要做什么。” 正确的？
It's a slide. It's not a collaborative.
这是一个滑梯。 这不是合作项目。
So when you are uh dating, when you're
所以，当你恋爱、
engaged, it's very important to begin to
订婚的时候，非常重要的一点是，
look at are you making decisions
你们是否一起做决定
together? Do you have the ability to
？ 你们有能力
make decisions together? Right? Deciding
共同做出决定吗？ 正确的？ 决定
verse sliding. Very important. Another
诗句滑动。 非常重要。 另一个对
one that's touchy for a lot of people,
很多人来说都很敏感的问题，
but it is what it is, is, you know, do
但事实就是如此，那就是，你知道，
you have physical attraction? There's
你们之间有生理上的吸引力吗？ 对此存在
there's a massive debate. I I don't
激烈的争论。 我不
understand why there's still a debate
明白为什么这个问题还有争论的余地
over this. is that every bit of science
。 所有科学研究都
suggests to us that if you have zero I'm
表明，如果你和伴侣之间没有任何吸引力（我指的是完全
talking about zero physical attraction,
没有身体上的吸引力），那么这段感情不会有任何结果
it's going nowhere. Like it's going
。 感觉就像原地踏步
nowhere. But if you have minimal
。 但是，如果你对对方的
physical attraction, it doesn't mean rip
身体吸引力很低，这并不意味着你会有脱
the clothes off energy, but if you have
衣服的冲动，但如果你对对方的
minimal physical attraction, then that
身体吸引力很低，那么这种冲动
could build because you could be, you
可能会逐渐增强，因为你
know, you could be sapioexual where it's
知道，你可能属于智性恋，也就是由
the intellect that drives you. But you
智力驱动的性行为。 但你
still have to have a minimal level of
仍然需要具备最低限度的
physical attraction. And then what we
身体吸引力。 然后我们
see is that over time attraction can
看到，随着时间的推移，吸引力
definitely grow, but it needs to start
肯定会增长，但它需要从某个
somewhere. So you think about physical
地方开始。 所以你会考虑外表
attraction, you think about the ability
吸引力、
to make decisions, compatibility in
决策能力、
values, also attachment style. These
价值观的契合度，以及依恋类型。
become, I think, the foundational pieces
我认为，这些构成了建立
to having a a a compatible relationship.
良好关系的基础要素。
But then there's this small little piece
但还有一小段
that I want to throw out. And this is
我想补充的内容。
US that I find to be fascinating is the
我发现美国的一些研究非常有趣，比如
marriage rate, you know, in the UK as
结婚率，英国的结婚率也是如此
well. It it it hovers, you know, between
。 你知道，离婚率徘徊在
let's say 35 and 50%, depending on who
35% 到 50% 之间，这取决于
who you're talking to, or should I say
你和谁交谈，或者我应该说
the divorce rate does 35 to 50%. So the
离婚率在 35% 到 50% 之间。 所以，
divorce on average. Now, if you were to
平均而言，近一半的伴侣最终都会离婚。 如果
just take out
只剔除
couples who have been engaged for two
订婚两年的情侣
years, what do you think that does to
，你认为这会对
the divorce rate? So, they've been
离婚率产生什么影响？ 所以，他们
engaged for two years and then they get
订婚两年后
married.
结婚了。
Uh, I think the divorce rate goes down.
嗯，我认为离婚率会下降。
Exactly. It goes down dramatically. Some
确切地。 它急剧下降。
people say it goes down to 20 20 22%.
有人说会降到 20 20 22%。
Right. chance of getting divorced if
正确的。 如果
you've been if you had a long
你有过一段较长的
engagement.
订婚期，那么你离婚的几率会比较高。   是的
Yes. Now, why would that be? The reason
。 为什么会这样呢？ 原因在于
why is because you're able to test out
你可以检验
all of these theories. You're able to
所有这些理论。 你能够
see your partner in the most adverse
在最不利的情况下观察你的伴侣，看看
circumstance and see, do they still show
他们是否
up as as true?
依然如故？   是的
Yeah. Can they still make a decision
。 他们还能
with me, you know, or do they
和我一起做决定吗？还是他们会
emotionally shut down and and and they
情感上封闭自己，然后
go away? So then when you look at
离开？ 所以，当你观察
why or the couples where you see divorce
离婚率高的原因或离婚现象普遍存在的夫妻群体时
being prevalent, it's in couples in one
，你会发现离婚现象主要发生在以下两类夫妻中
of two categories. One, they've known
。 第一，他们认识的时间
each other for a year or less, right?
不超过一年，对吧？
It's quick. Or when I say know each
很快。 或者当我说彼此认识时
other, they've been in committed
，他们可能
relationship for a year or less or
交往不到一年，也可能
they've been in committed relationship
交往了
for like 10 years and it's like
十年，
basically, you know, it was an ultimatum
基本上，你知道，这是个最后通牒，
and that's the reason why why why they
这就是他们
were married. So the 2 years of
结婚的原因。 所以
engagement I think is incredibly
我认为这两年的互动非常
important because it allows you to test
重要，因为它可以让你
out these compatibility metrics.
检验这些兼容性指标。
Two things there. So the first one I
这里有两件事。 所以，我
wanted to just jump back to because I
想直接回到第一个话题，因为我
found it really interesting and it's
觉得它非常有趣，而且
because of some of my friends in my
因为我的一些朋友也
can you be because you talked about
谈到了
physical attraction. Can you be
身体吸引力，所以我也一直在思考这个问题。 你可能会被
physically attracted to somebody but
某人的外表吸引，但却
then not have sexual attraction?
没有性吸引力吗？
Ah, okay.
哦，好的。
I say this because I remember in a past
我这么说是因为我记得在过去的一段
relationship I was physically attracted
感情中，我被她的外表所吸引，
to her but sexually I just it just
但在性方面我们却不
didn't work and that's why that
合拍，这就是那段
relationship ended. She was this
感情结束的原因。 她是个非常非常
beautiful girl. Her her bra like her
漂亮的女孩。 她的胸罩就像她的
mind, her intellect, she was super
思想、她的智慧一样，她非常
smart. She was super funny. She was just
聪明。 她超级搞笑。 她就是
everything. I think there was a point
一切。 我觉得在
before we went to have sex
我们发生性关系之前，
that I thought, "This is it. This is the
我曾想过：“就是他了。就是他了
one."
。”
We then went to have sex
然后我们就去做了性爱，
and I I've never [clears throat] said
我以前从未说过这样的话。（清嗓子）
this before. I remember getting up
我记得我起身
and going over to my phone and like
走到手机旁，
afterwards like and saying to one of my
然后对我的一个
best mates, I just going, "I don't think
好朋友说：“我觉得
I can ever see her again." See, I I
我再也见不到她了。” 我
wonder how much of this though plays
想知道这其中有多少因素真正影响到
into to to to foreplay really because
前戏，因为
have you have you heard about uh erotic
你听说过情色
blueprint?
蓝图吗？
I've heard about it. I think I heard it
我听说过这件事。 我好像是
on that Goop show.
在Goop的节目里听到的。
Okay. Yeah. Yeah, it was it was on Goop,
好的。 是的。 是的，Goop 上也有
too.
。
Oh, really? Yeah, I watched that. Yeah.
哦真的吗？ 是的，我看过。 是的。
So, you know, so and and I I I buy into
所以，你知道，我认同
that theory, which you know, the overall
这个理论，你知道，它的总体
premise is is that, you know, we all um
前提是，你知道，我们所有人，
we we all become sexually stimulated in
我们所有人受到性刺激的
different ways.
方式都不同。   是的
Yeah.
。
Right. And the the thought is that men
正确的。 人们普遍认为，男人随时都
are just ready all the time. Like, you
准备好了。 就像，你
know,
知道，是的
Yeah.
。   感觉
It's like we're like we're just ready,
我们就像已经准备好了，
you know, come on in the room like we're
你知道，就像我们已经准备好了一样，走进房间吧
just ready.
。
But that's not the case. You know, some
但事实并非如此。 你知道，对
of us it's about, you know, contextual,
我们中的一些人来说，这关乎语境，
you know, some of us, and this is men
你知道，对我们中的一些人来说，这指的是男人
and women, right? It's some of it's it's
和女人，对吧？
it's it's romantic, you know, some is
你知道，其中有些是浪漫的，有些是
you you need something that to people
你需要一些在别人看来很
would call bizarre, you know, going on.
奇怪的事情发生。
Kink.
纠结。
Kink. Yeah. Some BDSM, you know, going
纠结。 是的。 你知道，里面有些BDSM的成分
on. So, so that's why I I wonder how
。 所以，这就是为什么我想知道，
stimulation in that situation versus you
在那种情况下，有多少是性刺激导致的，又有多少是你
not being sexually attracted to the
对那个人没有性吸引力
person. So, I wish we could almost go
。 所以，我希望我们几乎可以回到过去，
back and and I could and I could be your
而我也可以，很遗憾，我可以成为你
sexual surrogate unfortunately in the
在房间里的性伴侣
room.
。   是的
Yeah. She's got a baby now. She's got a
。 她现在有孩子了。 她有个
[laughter] husband. She's
（笑）丈夫。 她和
You're with Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. But it
你在一起，是的。 是的。 是的。 但正是这件事让
just it it it was it made me pivot. I
我改变了方向。 我
think you're actually spot on because
觉得你说的完全正确，因为
what I came to learn a couple of years
几年后我才明白，
later was that I had this one sort of
我对
one-dimensional view of what sex was and
性的理解是一种片面的看法，就像
then as I've said on this podcast once
我之前在这个播客里说过的那样，
before when I started viewing sex as
当我开始把性看作是
potentially a different set of languages
一套不同的语言时，
and I thought [__] I'm speaking English
我想，操，我在说英语，
maybe she's speaking Spanish.
也许她在说西班牙语。   是的
Yes.
。
You know and I need to learn a new
你知道，我需要学习一门新
language in order to have um an
语言才能进行
effective uh um sexual conversation.
有效的性方面的对话。
Everything changed.
一切都变了。
Absolutely. And it changed for one of my
绝对地。 我的一位
best friends, too, cuz he was having a
好朋友的情况也发生了改变，因为他
similar issue with his sex life. And I
的性生活也遇到了类似的问题。 我
said, "What if you just saw it as like
说：“如果你把这想象成
your girlfriend speaks a different sex
你的女朋友说着另一种性爱
language? You're speaking one and you're
语言呢？你用一种语言跟她交流，然后你会说
like, "H, I'm unsatisfied." Cuz she's
，‘嗯，我不满足。’因为她用
speaking Spanish and she's going, "Uh,
西班牙语跟你交流，她会说，‘呃，
I'm unsatisfied." She wants touch. She
我不满足。’她想要触摸。她
wants the the 30 minute non-penetrative
想要那30分钟的非插入式
buildup.
前戏。
Yes.
没错。
You want to tie her up. You want to gag
你想把她绑起来。你想堵住她的嘴，
it gag her and whip it and all that kind
鞭打她，诸如此类的
of kinky BDSM stuff,
变态BDSM玩法，
right? You need to talk.
对吧？你需要沟通。
You need to talk and language.
你需要用另一种语言沟通。
Another language. And then also too,
另一种语言。还有，
because you dropped penetration in
因为你刚才提到了插入
there. This is something that most men,
。这是大多数男人，
I mean, men, we need to know this is
我的意思是，男人，我们需要知道的，
that the vast majority, 70 to 80% of
绝大多数，70%到80%的
women need clitoral stimulation, not
女性需要的是阴蒂刺激，而
just penetrative.
不仅仅是插入。
And I and and see, I mean, this is see
而且，你看，我的意思是，
this is this is where um the feedback
这就是反馈
once again.
再次出现的地方。
We have no feedback loop. you know
我们没有反馈机制。你知道，
promote porn [laughter]
推广色情片[笑声]，
that is our teacher you know that's our
那就是我们的 老师，你知道，那是我们的
teacher and what we have to understand
老师，我们必须明白的
is is no there are I love what you're
是，不，有很多
saying there are different languages
不同的语言，
sexual languages you have to understand
性爱的语言，你必须理解
how your partner the language that they
你的伴侣用什么语言来
speak sex in and you have to deliver it
表达性爱，你必须回应它。
and that's also why communication is the
这也是为什么沟通是
bedrock of all relationships it really
所有关系的基础，确实如此。是的，你说
yeah that's so true thinking about how I
得太对了，我在想我本
could have fixed that situation. Um, but
可以如何解决这个问题。嗯，但是，
because I, you're right, I totally
你说得对，我完全
dismissed it and I didn't do any work.
忽略了它，我没有做任何努力。
That was the very much characteristic of
这很符合
my younger self, which was if something
我年轻时的性格，那就是如果有什么事——无论是
and this is relationship, sex, whatever
关系、性，还是其他什么——
it was. If something isn't perfect now,
如果现在不完美，那就直接
go just run. Don't do any work to like
跑。不去努力
to have the conversation to to fix it to
沟通，不去解决问题，不去
have empathy for someone else might have
体谅别人，因为别人可能有
a different opinion or a different bias
不同的观点、不同的偏见
or a different attachment style. If it's
或不同的依恋模式。如果它
not perfect, I would dash. Yeah,
不完美，我就逃之夭夭。是的，
I'll go in search of perfect, which
我会去追求完美，而完美
doesn't exist.
并不存在。是的
Yeah. And but this is I mean, you know,
。但你知道，
this is all of us. This is this is
这其实是我们所有人的通病。这就是
immaturity. And that's the beauty of
不成熟。 这就是学习的美妙之处
learning, you know, as you grow older.
，你知道，随着年龄的增长。
On that point of seeking perfection, um
关于追求完美这一点，嗯，
and I asked it a second ago, but we got
我刚才也问过，但我们聊到了
we went off on the sex thing. Um that
性。嗯，这
sounds weird. Please [laughter] don't
听起来有点怪。拜托[笑]别点
click that.
开那个链接。
Um do we know what we're looking for?
嗯，我们知道自己在寻找什么吗？
Are people good at saying this is what I
人们擅长说“这就是我
want?
想要的”吗？
Hells no. We are terrible. We're all
当然不。我们很糟糕。在爱情方面，我们都有
biased when it when it comes to to to
偏见
love, you know. Um I've done a lot of
，你知道。嗯，我做了很多
research around biases. And when it
关于偏见的研究。
comes to love, it's like we're wearing
说到爱情，我们就像戴着一副
known to known to human beings. We're
人类已知最模糊的眼镜。我们在
love life. You know, normally we are
爱情生活中做出任何理性的决定都很糟糕。你知道，通常我们都在
looking for ourselves. Like we literally
寻找自己。我们真的就是在
are are looking for ourselves. It's it's
寻找自己。
funny to me um when you see some when
我觉得很有趣的是，当
when you ask someone, well, what is your
你问别人“你喜欢什么类型？”的时候，你会说，“嗯，嗯，什么
type? Which I hate that phrase, but
类型？”我讨厌这句话，但
you'll say, well, well, what is your
你会说，嗯，嗯， 你喜欢哪种
type? And typically people will describe
类型？通常人们会描述
someone who's very much like themselves.
一个和自己非常相似的人。
Very much like themselves in so many of
在很多方面都非常相似
these categories. And so we we are
。所以，我们
horrendously bad at not only identifying
不仅不擅长识别
what works well with us, but then making
什么适合自己，更不擅长做出
the selection. And on top of that, most
选择。而且，大多数
women don't make the selection. It's
女性并不做选择。
typically the man who makes the
通常是男性做出
selection. And this is where I say that
选择。而
what I like, what I'm seeing now is more
我喜欢现在看到的是，越来越多的
women are are be are consciously
女性开始有意识地
choosing who and what they want in their
选择她们想要的伴侣，而不是
who are always selected.
总是被动地接受选择。
Why does that happen? Why are why are
为什么会这样？为什么
women not choosing? Is it because Yeah.
女性不再主动选择？是因为……嗯，
Give me because
给我……
Yeah. I mean, it's it's it's it's
嗯。我的意思是，是
because of, you know, the craziness of
因为这个
of of the world and how we've evolved.
世界的疯狂以及我们自身的发展。
You know, if you if you think about it
想想看，
was the pill that was one of the first
避孕药是
liberation points for women when it came
女性在约会方面获得解放的最初标志之一
to when it came to dating. I mean, and
。
you think about it's that's not that
想想看，那其实并没有过去多久
long ago. We're talking about the 60s.
。我们说的是……  60年代。
We're talking about the 70s really when
我们其实是在说70年代，也就是
the when the when the pill became
避孕药开始
invogue, you know, if you will, at least
流行的时候，至少
in the United States. And what that
在美国是这样。这让
allowed was for women to finally have a
女性在约会方面终于有了
little bit of choice when it came to
一些选择权
dating. Before that, it was it was
。在此之前，
virtually men making the selection,
几乎都是男性在做
making the choice. You're mine or you're
选择。要么你是我的，要么你
pregnant, so you're definitely mine. And
怀孕了，所以你肯定是我的。就是这样
that was it. And then you saw a little
。然后，
bit of liberation come from the pill,
避孕药带来了一些解放，
which was incredible. But then also,
这真是太棒了。但现在，
what's great now is the dating apps. I
约会软件也很棒。我
know the dating apps get a lot of a lot
知道约会软件
of stick for whatever reasons and yes we
因为各种原因经常受到批评，没错，我们
should always hold dating apps
应该始终对约会软件
accountable but what's beautiful is that
负责，但它的优点在于，
you do have dating apps where you have
约会软件确实
given women a lot more choice and
给了女性更多的选择和
control in the dating experience which
控制权，这很
is important and even when you look at
重要。即使你看看
the studies and you look at the dating
研究，看看那些由女性
app ecosystems that are that are uh led
主导的约会软件生态系统，
They're less crude. You know, the list
它们也更安全，更文明。你知道，好处还有很多
goes on and on.
。
Interesting. So, are you saying that we
很有意思。那么，你是 你说
contrast is is tends to be better for
对比比
compatibility than finding someone who's
寻找一个和
a replication of yourself?
自己一模一样的人更有利于找到合适的伴侣？
Uh, all right. That that's a good one.
嗯，好的。这说得对。
So, a bit of a a bit of contrast, right?
所以，有点对比，对吧？
A a bit of it. It's it's almost like
有点。这几乎就像
going back to the weak tie theory. You
回到了弱关系理论。你
know, you want someone I think
知道，你想要找一个……我想……
Well, let me say this. the the best
嗯，这么说吧。
matches I've seen are based on that
我见过最好的匹配都是基于
blueprint that I outlined from
我概述的那个蓝图，从
attachment style all the way down to
依恋类型一直到
physical attraction. But then context
外貌吸引力。但情境
also plays a large role. You know, if I
也起着很大的作用。你知道，如果我把
were to place you on a desolate island
你和某人放在一个荒岛上
with someone, I guarantee that person is
，我保证过一段时间后，这个人会
going to be the love of your life after
成为你一生的挚爱
a while.
。
You're going to have babies.
你们会生孩子。
You're gonna have lots of babies.
你们会生很多孩子。
They're going to be, you know, your
他们会成为你的
soul. You're gonna think they're your
灵魂伴侣。你会认为他们是你的
soulmate, right? So context plays a
灵魂伴侣，对吧？所以情境起着非常非常非常重要的
large large large large role which is
作用，这就是
why
为什么
it's interesting to see how politics
政治
plays a role in dating. You know just 20
在约会中扮演的角色很有趣。你知道，就在20
years ago politics was insignificant in
年前，政治…… 在
dating. It was not a topic that was
约会中，政治观点并不重要。这根本不是一个会被
brought up. Definitely not brought up on
提及的话题。第一次约会时肯定不会提到
a first date. But you know, if your
。但是，如果你的
partner was on was has an opposing
伴侣持有相反的
political view, it's completely fine.
政治观点，那完全没问题。
Today, it's one of the top metrics
如今，政治观点已成为衡量
behind whether or not you want to match
你是否想与
someone is is politics. There have been
某人匹配的重要标准之一。
some really interesting studies that
一些非常有趣的研究
showed that I mean e even how sexually
表明，即使
obsessed men are, right? We still would
男性对性欲如此强烈，我们仍然会
turn down, well, it depends on on who
拒绝——当然，这取决于
you're talking to, but there's a
你和谁交谈——但确实有
significant percentage of men, but a
相当一部分男性，以及
vast majority of women who would not
绝大多数女性，不会
have sex with someone that they find
与自己觉得
physically attractive, but yet have
外表吸引但
opposing political beliefs.
政治观点相反的人发生性关系。
I mean, that that but that's the
我的意思是，这就是
context. That's the day and age that we
现状。这就是我们
live in. So, so context, I think, plays
所处的时代。所以，我认为，环境也
plays a role as well. Do we have to work
起着一定的作用。我们真的需要
hard to find someone? Because I think
努力寻找另一半吗？因为我认为
there's there's kind of a prevailing
现在有一种普遍的
narrative that serendipity will solve it
说法，认为缘分会解决一切
for us. The world has changed
。世界已经发生了
tremendously. We don't have we don't go
翻天覆地的变化。我们不再需要……
to church like we used to. We don't have
我们不再像以前那样去教堂了。我们的生活中也没有
these pubs or that sort of institutions
酒吧或类似的
of community in our lives. So, we're
社区机构。所以，我们
like predominantly more lonely than ever
比以往任何时候都更加孤独，独自
living in full white walls in big old
住在大城市的白色墙壁里
cities alone. H do we have to work hard
。我们真的需要努力
to find that person? Do we have to put
寻找那个对的人吗？我们需要
in work?
付出努力吗？
Yeah, that that's that's a great
是的，这是一个很好的
question. I I think we should I think we
问题。我认为我们
should put in the work. I think that we
应该付出努力。我认为我们
should put effort towards anything that
应该为
we have interest in. So if a romantic
自己感兴趣的事情付出努力。所以，如果
interest is something that you want to
你想要一段浪漫的感情
have, you you you should put the work
，你就应该付出努力
in. But I don't necessarily think it's
。但我认为这并不一定是指把精力放在
else. It's about putting the work into
别人身上。
you, right? and just elevating you,
而是要把精力放在自己身上，对吧？提升自己，
optimizing you, making you the best you
优化自己，让自己
can be, upping your communication,
成为最好的自己，提高沟通能力，
right? Understanding how to build
对吧？学会如何建立
emotional ties, right? Understanding how
情感联系，对吧？学会如何
to make great decisions, understanding
做出正确的决定，学会
how to be a great listener, critical
如何成为一个优秀的倾听者和批判性思考
thinker, right? All of these things are
者，对吧？所有这些都会
going to help you in all aspects of life
在你生活的方方面面帮助你，
and definitely in your romantic life.
而且肯定会对你有所帮助。 在你的恋爱生活中。
So, that's the that's where the hard
所以，这就是
work needs to go in. But we're in an
需要努力的地方。但我们现在处在一个
interesting place because
有趣的境地，因为
every generation believes their
每一代人都认为自己那
generation had it the hardest when it
一代在
comes to finding a spouse. This is
寻找伴侣方面最艰难。这种情况
throughout time. Talking to my
贯穿古今。我跟我
grandfather, my grandfather, oh man, you
爷爷聊起这件事，哦，天哪，你绝对
won't believe how hard I had it, you
想象不到我当年有多难
know. And my grandfather had three
。我爷爷只有三个
options.
选择。
Three options. Three options, right?
三个选择。三个选择，对吧？
Small village in Jamaica. Three options.
牙买加的一个小村庄。三个选择。
Three people.
三个人。
But what I find interesting is there's a
但我发现有趣的是，
a book paradox of choice by Barry
巴里·施瓦茨写了一本关于选择的悖论的书，
Schwarz and he's the less is more right
他认为少即是多。
and what's interesting is that we have
有趣的是，我们
more options today than say my
今天拥有的选择比我
grandfather had in his day but it's we
爷爷那一代要多得多，但我们对
make because we believe we have endless
所做的选择却更不满意，因为我们误以为我们有无穷无尽的
choice. That's the real problem that we
选择。这才是我们真正的问题所在
have. So you think about you go onto a
。想想看，你打开一个
dating app, right? How many people can
约会软件，对吧？
you swipe through in a dating app?
你可以在一个约会软件上滑动浏览多少人？
Endless. It's endless. You you could
无穷无尽。真的无穷无尽。
literally 10,000 if you want to. And the
如果你愿意，你甚至可以滑动浏览一万个。 我的
thought is that you have an option. All
想法是，你拥有一个选择。所有
10,000 are option. So because you have
10000个选项都是选择。所以，因为你有
10,000 options and you pick one, there's
10000个选择，而你只选了一个，那么这个
less value that you have in the one. But
选择的价值就降低了。但
if I flipped it around, maybe this is
如果我换个角度想，也许这就是个好
idea. See, I should pitch you on this
主意。你看，我现在就应该跟你讲讲这个
idea right now. All right. Dating app.
想法。好的。约会软件。
Yeah,
对
Because here, so here's my thought. So
，这就是我的方案。约会软件，但你每周只有三个选择。有意思。你觉得怎么样？你觉得怎么样？因为我的
So here's my thought, right? The thought
想法
is that you place more value
是，你会更看重
in the option you choose,
你选择的那个选项，
right? And that's ultimately I think
对吧？而这最终我认为是
what the challenge is in this day and
当今
age. It's about we think you know we're
时代的挑战所在。我们认为自己
that we have we have endless option.
拥有无限的选择，所以反而降低了对每个选项的重视程度。
So true. The the issue with the idea is
没错。这个想法的问题在于，
in a world where there are other apps
在一个存在其他应用程序的世界里，
like if that app existed and it was the
如果这个应用程序存在，而且是
only app then it would be the conversion
唯一的应用程序，那么
rate from first date to marriage I think
从第一次约会到结婚的转化率我认为
would be considerably harder um higher.
会高得多。
However, in a world where I can also use
然而，在
Tinder or Hinge when they're going to
如果 Tinder 或 Hinge 能给
give me 10,000 options, I [laughter]
我提供一万个选择，我（笑）
think people will always choose option.
觉得人们总是会选择其他选择。
So, I I think we'd have a problem
所以，我觉得我们会面临
getting users
用户流失的问题，
because they'd go, "Well, I'd rather
因为他们会想：“我宁愿
have a thousand guys to choose from or a
有一千个男生或者
thousand women to choose from." Um, but
一千个女生可以选择。” 嗯，
but your point is so spot on that a lack
但是你的观点非常正确，选择少
um means we care. We'll invest more and
意味着我们更在意。我们会投入更多资源，更加
work harder on the ones we do have to
努力地开发现有的功能，确保
make to make them work. Whereas, if I if
它们能够正常运行。而如果我和
I meet you on a date and I don't feel
你约会，感觉不够
like it's perfection, I'll go, "Fuck
完美，我就会想：“算了，不去了
this. I I got 37 men in my Tinder DMs
。” 我在 Tinder 上收到了 37 个男人的私信，他们也
that wanted to meet me as well. So, I go
想和我见面。 于是，我就去
try one of them.
试了其中一个。   是的
Yep.
。
And there's always We're always
而且我们总是要
contending with the false
面对其他
highlight reel X uh reality of those 36
36 个男人的虚假光环和现实
other men, right?
，对吧？
Cuz they looked perfect. They did.
因为它们看起来完美无瑕。 他们做到了。
They chose the best three selfies and
他们选出了他最好的三张自拍照，照片里
they had he had a Rolex on and he you
他戴着劳力士手表，你
know, so and then you meet him and you
知道，然后你见到他，你
go [__] [laughter]
就想：操！[笑声]
what?
什么？
What? But I'm going to go to the 36
什么？ 但我会去其他36个地方
others. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. And that's
。 是的。 是的。 确切地。 那将是
a horrific spiral.
一个可怕的恶性循环。
Um, another question I had was about
嗯，我的另一个问题是关于
honesty from the jump.
从一开始就坦诚相待。
You go on a first date, you meet
你去参加第一次约会，认识了
someone. How honest should I be?
某人。 我应该诚实到什么程度？
Should I tell them about my childhood
我应该
trauma on the first date? [laughter]
在第一次约会时告诉对方我童年的创伤经历吗？  [笑声]
Like, is that being authentic or should
这就算是真诚吗？还是只是在
is that offloading?
逃避现实？   是的
Yeah. Yeah. Well, you know, Chris Rock
。 是的。 嗯，你知道，克里斯·洛克
said it best. You know, when you meet
说得最好。 你知道，当你和
someone, especially on a date, you're
某人见面时，尤其是在约会时，你
not meeting them. You're meeting their
并不是在真正地认识他们。 你知道，你要见的是他们的
representative, you know. So from that
代表。 所以从这个
standpoint, we have to understand that
角度来看，我们必须明白，
happens especially on these first dates
尤其是在第一次约会时，会存在一种界限协商，
and it is that that tennis game again,
而这不就是网球比赛
right? So what you're trying to do
吗？ 所以你
ultimately is you're trying to and and
最终想做的是，你试图……
let me even back up. Can I say this
让我先退一步说说。
about the one is that I think we I think
关于第一次约会，我想说的是，我认为我们
most of us do the first date completely
大多数人第一次约会都做得
wrong. Entirely wrong. We set ourselves
一塌糊涂。 完全错误。 我们
up from the jump to fail miserably and
从一开始就注定要惨败，注定
be disappointed. And the reason why is
要失望。 原因在于，第
because it the the first date is too
一次约会太过
intricate. It's too big. You know, it's
复杂。 它太大了。 你知道，这是
dinner. But to prepare for dinner, I'm
晚餐时间。 但为了准备晚餐，我
going to buy a new whatever. You know,
打算买个新东西。 你知道吗，
I'm going to get my hair done. You know,
我要去做头发了。 你知道，
I'm going to get this. I'm going to buy
我肯定会得到这个。 我打算买
this new thing. I'm going to get the car
这个新东西。 我要去
wash. I'm going to do all this stuff.
洗车。 我打算做所有这些事。
We've spent we've invested so much that
我们投入了太多，以至于
we've set oursel up for failure. Also, a
注定要失败。 坦白地说，
first date, quite honestly, over a
第一次约会，比如共进
dinner is an interview. It always turns
晚餐，其实就是一次面试。 总是会
into an interview. And then the culture
变成采访。 然后，
I've noticed in the UK is fascinating is
我注意到英国的一种文化很有意思，虽然
that this is not everyone, but typically
不是每个人都这样，但
I notice is we're going to get
我通常注意到，我们在
completely pissed before the date. Like,
约会前都会喝得酩酊大醉。 比如，
so we can talk to each other. So, we're
这样我们就可以互相交流了。 所以，我们接下来就只管
just going to drink drink drink. Okay,
喝喝喝。 好了，
now let's talk to each other. And so it
现在我们来聊聊。 因此，
becomes we set ourselves up for having a
我们注定要付出
very costly date in time, effort, res,
非常高昂的时间、精力、
all resources. Instead, it sounds so
资源等代价。 相反，听起来却很
simple. I like meetups. Let's not let's
简单。 我喜欢聚会。 咱们还是别给约会这
date situation. Let's call it a meetup.
件事施加压力了。 我们就叫它聚会吧。
30 minutes. Let's have coffee, right?
30分钟。 咱们喝咖啡吧？
The reason why I love that or a walk.
我喜欢散步的原因是……
Sounds stupid, right? No, a walk for 30
听起来很蠢，对吧？ 不，步行30
minutes. Let's just go walk at lunch.
分钟。 午休的时候我们去散步吧。
Let's go go take a walk. The reason why
我们去散步吧。
I love that is because the expectation
我喜欢这种情况的原因是，
is so much lower in that situation. So
在这种情况下，人们的期望值要低得多。
much lower. The cost so much lower,
低得多。 成本低了很多，
right? So the investment,
对吧？ 所以，这就是投资，
right? So much lower. So therefore that
对吧？ 低得多。 因此，
return on investment
投资回报率
potentially so much higher. But then
可能会更高。 但从
also psychologically what I love is is
心理层面来说，我喜欢的是，
is happening is is if it's coffee,
无论是喝咖啡、
caffeine, if it's a walk, it's
摄入咖啡因，还是散步，都会产生
endorphins going, right? those help us
内啡肽，对吧？ 这些都能帮助我们
to bond, right? Opposed to alcohol
建立联系，对吗？ 与酒精
that's a depressant, right? It's it's
这种抑制剂相反，对吧？ 它，它，它正在
it's it's doing it's doing the opposite.
做，它正在做相反的事情。
So, in terms of elucidating ourselves
所以，为了更好地进行深入
for great conversation
交流，
and preparing ourselves for success, a
并为成功做好准备，
walk or a coffee is great. The other
散步或喝杯咖啡都是不错的选择。 另一方面，
part of that is I've had mill like not
我拥有的是百万级的资金，而不是数百万级的
millions. I've had let's say thousands
。 我已经接待过成千上万的
of clients who I've said okay tell is in
客户，我告诉他们，
particular this is for ladies telling
特别是对于女士来说，
men tell the guy that you you want to
告诉男士你想
meet him for coffee in the day.
在白天和他一起喝咖啡。
A lot of guys are like I'm not doing
很多男生都说“我不干
that.
那种事”。
Yeah cuz they want to get laid.
对，因为他们想找人上床。
[laughter]
[笑声]
They're like I'm not doing that. Right.
他们说我不会那样做。 正确的。
So right away
所以它立刻
it's a good filter.
就是一个很好的过滤器。
It's a great filter. Yeah, it's
这是一个很棒的过滤器。 是的，
easy filter for you, you know. So,
对你来说过滤起来很容易。 所以，
that's part of that. And then if it
这是其中的一部分。 如果一切
works well, and when I say if it works
顺利，我说的顺利是指，
well is you just need two things on that
在那次聚会上你只需要两样东西
meetup.
。
Are you physically attracted to them
你对他们有
minimally?
最低限度的生理吸引力吗？
And then did they listen to you? So, if
然后他们听你的了吗？ 所以，如果
you have the ability to communicate,
你有沟通能力，
they listened critically, you listen
他们认真倾听，你也
critically, and you're physically
认真倾听，并且你们彼此有生理上的
attracted. That is chemistry. Because we
吸引力。 这就是化学。 因为我们
have a hard time defining what is
很难定义什么是
chemistry. You say, "What is chemistry?
化学。 你会问：“什么是化学反应？那种
What's the buzz? What what does that
感觉是什么？它到底
mean? And everyone's like, I don't know.
意味着什么？”然后每个人都会说，我不知道。
I don't know. It is, I think, one part
我真的不知道。我觉得，它一部分是
physical attraction, mutual physical
身体上的吸引，彼此的身体
attraction, another part critical
吸引，另一部分是认真
listening. Listening. If you have that,
倾听。倾听。如果你具备了这些，
you have enough to move forward and then
你们就有足够的基础继续前进，然后
see each other in another environment.
在另一个环境中再次相遇。
You know,
你知道，
it's so true because I just reflecting
这真的很有道理，因为我反思了一下，
on how many of my friends, both men and
我的很多朋友，无论
women, will come back from a date that
男女，都会在约会失败后回来，然后怨
didn't work out and just resentfully
气冲冲地
talk about how much they've spent and
抱怨自己花了多少钱，
[laughter] how and how and how much it c
[笑] 抱怨花了多少时间，花了
how much money it cost them and the
多少钱，还有做
preparation of the facial and the hair
面部护理、头发
and the nails and and they sit there
和指甲等等，他们坐在那里
resentfully and it's all you you you're
怨气冲冲。你说得对，
right, bringing that level of
把这种
expectation to a to a first encounter,
期望值带到第一次见面上，
you know, know Mo Gadat sat here and
你知道吗？莫·加达特
said we're happy when our expectations
说过，当我们对生活应有的期待得到满足时，我们会感到快乐；而当我们对
of how life is supposed to be going go
生活不满意时，
are met and we're unhappy when our
我们会感到不快乐。 当我们对
expectations of how life is supposed to
生活应有的期待落空时
be going go unmet. I'm coming in with
。我带着
one hell of an expectation that you're
极高的期望来找你，希望你能
going to be my husband.
成为我的丈夫。
Yes,
是的，
I've put in all the work, all the
我投入了所有的努力、所有的
investment, the time, 3 hours, and then
付出、所有的时间，整整三个小时，
if you fall anywhere below that for
如果你因为
whatever reason, I'm probably looking
任何原因达不到我的期望，我可能就会想
for, you know,
，
oh god, it's not you're almost setting
天哪，你投入了这么多，岂不是注定要失败？
Yes. And you know what, you you were
是的。你知道吗，你刚才说的很有道理，
point there is that when you've made
当你投入了
that investment, what you end up doing
这么多之后，
is you're looking for reasons to weed
你最终会想方设法把
them out.
他们淘汰掉。是啊。
Cuz you're like, I mean, I did all this.
因为你会想，我做了这么多。是
Yeah. I mean, his trainers.
啊。我是说，他的运动鞋。是
Yeah. [laughter]
啊。[笑声]
What What trainers is this guy wearing?
什么？这家伙穿的是什么运动鞋？我的
Oh my god. You see that train? Those are
天哪。你看到那鞋跟了吗？那是
last year's trainers.
去年的旧鞋了。
I bought new shoes for this [__] And
我为了这事儿买了新鞋。而
he's [laughter] Yeah.
他[笑声]是啊。是
Yeah. It's crazy. Crazy. Crazy. Crazy.
啊。太疯狂了。太疯狂了。 真是疯了。疯了。
What what are you struggling with in
你在
your relationship?
感情方面遇到了什么困难？
Oh man, you know, it is time
哦，天哪，你知道，真的需要好好相处一段时间
really
。
time.
高质量的相处时间。
It is it is it is I would say time but
我得说，是需要，但真的是
quality time because I am you know in
高质量的相处时间，因为你知道，
right now I'm predominantly doing
我现在主要在做
television work and and I've been in TV
电视工作，而且我
now you know for uh since Oprah you know
从奥普拉·温弗瑞的节目开始就在电视圈了，你知道，
so 12 13 years. So, so it's it's been a
大概有12、13年了。所以，时间过得挺
while. And one thing I've noticed about
久的。我注意到
the television space is that there are
电视圈的一个特点是，
moments when you're hot and there are
有时候你会很火，有时候
moments when you're not. And when you're
你会很冷门。当你很
hot, it's that's the time to leverage.
火的时候，就是要好好利用的时候。
And so, you have to you're already
所以，你必须更加
working your ass off, but you better
努力，你已经很努力了，但你最好
work it off even more. And so, I'm in
更加努力。我
that zone right now. I mean, I'm
现在就处于这种状态。我的意思是，我很
blessed. I'm co-hosting two shows. I'm
幸运。我主持两个节目。我
contributing to three shows, one in the
参与制作三个节目，一个在
States, two here in the UK. So, it's one
美国，两个在英国。所以，
of these where I'm constantly work every
我每天都在工作
day. Every day I'm working. Every day
。 我每天都在工作。
I'm working. So, that time
我每天都在工作。所以，
with my wife, [snorts] that time with my
和妻子在一起的时间，（嗤之以鼻）和
children, that's the time that I wish I
孩子们在一起的时间，我多么希望
can get some back.
能够弥补这些时间的损失。
How are you negotiating that? How are
你是如何平衡这些的呢？
you serving the ball over the net in
用网球来比喻，你是如何把球打过网，
terms of the tennis analogy to make sure
确保妻子
like a priority and your family still
和家人仍然对你来说都是
feel like a priority?
最重要的呢？是的
Yeah, that that's a great one. I mean,
，这真是个好问题。我的意思是，要
finding those moments and making sure
找到那些相处的时光，确保
that we're in or should I say making
我们能够，或者应该说，
sure that we're intentional about the
确保我们有意识地珍惜我们
moments that we do have, right? So, this
拥有的这些时光，对吧？比如今天
morning, for example, before I came over
早上，在我来
here, we had breakfast together. Went
这里之前，我们一起吃了早餐。
out, had breakfast together, sat, talked
出去吃了早餐，坐下来，
with the dog, right? Those moments are
和狗狗聊聊天，对吧？这些时光是
immeasurable, right? Those moments,
无法估量的，对吧？那些时光，对吧
right? To have those moments together.
？能够拥有这些在一起的时光。
Um I dropped my boys off at school,
嗯，我送孩子们去学校了，
right? Walk you walked them 10 minutes
对吧？我送他们走了10分钟
to school to 10 minutes the other to the
到学校，然后又走了10分钟到公交
to the bus. Those moments immeasurable,
车站。这些时光是无法估量的。
you know, when I was, you know, getting
你知道，当我
helping them dress, tying their ties.
帮他们穿衣服、系领带的时候，
Those moments and making sure that I'm
那些时刻，我都确保自己
fully in those moments. Not I'm in that
完全沉浸其中。不是说我身处那个
moment, but I'm on my phone at the same
时刻，但我同时还在玩手机
time. I'm in that moment. Oh, I've got
。我明明身处那个时刻，却突然想：“哦，我得把
to post this on Instagram. No, phone
这个发到Instagram上。” 不行，手机得赶紧
goes away, right? Phone goes away. And
放下，对吧？手机得赶紧放下。
so, making sure that the moments that we
所以，我得确保自己能全心全意地投入到我们拥有的那些时刻中
have that I'm fully I'm fully in them.
。而且
And then also, I think gratitude is
，我认为感恩
something that is is very important and
非常重要，
I've been practicing this for I don't
我已经练习了
know six, seven years, but being
六七年了，就是要懂得
appreciative of those moments and then
欣赏那些时刻，然后
reflecting
反思
upon those, you know. So every morning
它们。所以每天
the first thing I do in the morning is I
早上，我做的第一件事就是有
I consciously think about the moments
意识地思考
yesterday that I'm appreciative of. And
昨天那些让我感恩的时刻。
what I find myself doing is I'm rarely
我发现自己很少会
thinking about oh I'm so happy this
想到“哦，工作中发生的这件事真让我高兴”
happened at work or I'm so happy about
或者“
the ratings of this. It's always man I'm
这个节目的收视率真让我高兴”。我总是会想到“哇，我
so happy that my son who's 11 held my
真高兴我的儿子……”  11岁的时候，他牵着我的
hand walking to the bus. He's 11 but he
手走向公交车站。他才11岁，却
still held my hand. You know, I'm so
依然牵着我的手。你知道吗，
happy that my son came over and he asked
我儿子过来让
me to tie his tie. He gave me a kiss on
我帮他系领带，我真的太开心了。他亲了亲我的
the cheek and said, "Thank you, Dad."
脸颊，说：“谢谢爸爸。”
Like, those are the moments that really
这些时刻真的让我感动不已
get to me. And that's what I I wake up
。我醒来后脑子里想的都是这些，
about it because I was in the moment
因为我当时
fully.
完全沉浸在那个瞬间。
And what's talk to me about the
那么，说说你
near-term then? What are you working on
近​​期的计划吧？你最近在忙些什么
in the near term? I know you've got we
？我知道你有很多收入来源，虽然我们
don't even talk about it today, but
今天还没谈到，但
you've got multiple revenue streams all
你有很多不同的收入来源
over the place. You're an entrepreneur.
。你是一位企业家。
You've got two t two or three TV shows
你同时在制作两三个电视节目，
which is absurd.
这简直太不可思议了。
Yes.
是的。
All of these things going on in your
你生活中有很多事情要做
life. What am I what give me a picture
。你能给我介绍一下
of your full your professional
你完整的职业
portfolio, per se?
履历吗？
Okay. So, so there there are a lot of
好的。所以，你有很多
things happening. Uh and they're all in
事情要做。 它们都属于
different categories. So, so on the
不同的类别。所以，在
television side, I am uh I'm co-hosting
电视方面，我……我是
Married at First Sight UK and I'm also
英国版《一见钟情》（Married at First Sight UK）的联合主持人，也是《名人
co-hosting Celebs Go Dating. We're in
约会》（Celebs Go Dating）的联合主持人。《
our 11th series of Slubs Go Dating and
名人约会》已经播出到第11季了，《一见钟情》也已经播出到第
our seventh uh of uh of Mered at First
7季了
Sight. So, so, so those are those are
。所以，这些都是比较重要的节目
big entities. I contribute to the Lraine
。我还为《莱恩
Show.
秀》（Lraine Show）撰稿。
Oh, yeah.
哦，对了。
And also to Steph's Pack Lunch.
还有《斯蒂芬的午餐》（Steph's Pack Lunch）。是的。
Yep.
在美国，我也是《
a contributor to Good Morning America.
早安美国》（Good Morning America）的撰稿人。
Right. So, that by itself or those are a
对。所以，光这些就够我
couple full-times, right? But that's
全职工作了，对吧？但这就是
that's kind of like the the TV side.
电视方面的情况。
Do you have a podcast?
你有播客吗？
I don't.
没有。
I I did like a years ago. I I did. But I
我几年前有过。真的有过。但
mean, quite honestly, looking at this
说实话，看着你，
and you know, you are and and this is me
你知道，我
not trying to trying to gas you up is
不是想吹捧你，
you are incredibly inspiring. Incredibly
你真的非常鼓舞人心。非常
inspiring. And I and you know what's
鼓舞人心。而且你知道
interesting is I I I I look at you and I
有趣的是，我看着你，
think, okay, God, this guy is younger
心想，天哪，这家伙
than me. You know, how is the he's he's
比我还年轻。你知道，他
so much younger than me and he's
比我年轻那么多，怎么还能
inspiring me, right? And what it is is
激励我呢？关键在于，
that you pursue excellence to a degree I
你追求卓越的程度，
don't know if I've ever witnessed. I'm
我以前从未见过。我
talking about I've worked with some of
指的是，我曾与
the top billionaires in the world. I've
世界上一些顶尖的亿万富翁共事，
interviewed I was a business columnist
我曾是《
for USA Today and I interviewed some of
今日美国》的商业专栏作家，我采访过一些
the most successful entrepreneurs
最成功的企业家，真的。
like period. And your level of pursuit
而你追求
of excellence surpasses
卓越的程度远超
them.
他们。
Where's my billion? Yeah, but [laughter]
我的亿万富翁呢？是啊，但是（笑）你
but see it's not about the but it's not
看，这不是关于钱的问题，这不是关于钱的问题，
about that you know you're and and and
你知道，你……
and so all I say is that so you are
所以我只想说，你
incredibly inspiring to me and to to to
对我以及很多人来说都极具启发性。
many people and to the question around
关于
the podcast is part of that inspiration
播客的问题，这种启发的一部分
is like
在于，
this is a great space you know to to get
这是一个很棒的领域，你知道，值得
into. So that's something that is in the
进入。所以，这确实是
back of my mind but I'm not actively
我脑海中的想法，但我并没有主动去
pursuing it.
追求。
That's very kind. It makes me feel
非常感谢。这让我感觉
really uncomfortable. That's why I
很不自在。这就是我
cracked that billion. I don't [laughter]
突破十亿的原因。我当时
know what to do with my face the whole
全程都不知道该怎么形容我的表情
time. I was like,
。我当时就想，
how do you feel? How do you feel today?
你感觉怎么样？你今天感觉如何？
It's a huge It's a huge compliment and I
这是莫大的赞美，
I I receive the compliment and I I I
我接受这份赞美，我也
believe what you're saying. It just, you
相信你说的。只是，你
know, it makes me feel uncomfortable cuz
知道，这让我感觉有点不自在，因为，
I you know, I don't know why it just
你知道，我不知道为什么，
makes me feel uncomfortable when I when
当我真的很
I really appreciate it and I believe
感激，并且相信
every word you said. Um I believe you
你说的每一个字的时候，我就是感觉有点不自在。嗯，我相信你
meant every word you said. Um, and I
说的每一个字都是真心话。嗯，我知道
our team will be successful in pretty
我们团队之所以能在几乎所有事情上取得成功，
much anything we do is because of what
就是因为
you said. So, it's because I think we
你刚才说的。所以，我认为是因为我们
care more about the small stuff.
更注重细节。是的
Yes.
。
And that's where for me, excellence
对我来说，卓越就
begins. We can all make the big
始于此。我们都能做出重大
decisions. To start a podcast is a big
决定。开办播客就是一个重大
decision. It doesn't guarantee success.
决定。但这并不能保证成功。成功在于那些看似
that are easy to do, but also easy not
容易做到，但却至关重要的小事。 很容易
to do that end up defining your
忽略这一点，而这最终会决定你的发展
trajectory. And over the last I think
轨迹。尤其是在过去
two years in particular actually because
两年里，因为
of this podcast and actually because
这个播客，也因为
it's so datacentric and I look at lines
它非常注重数据，我经常查看各种曲线
and charts and how one decision that
和图表，发现我和
like the team and I make or that Jack
团队，或者杰克
makes can just tilt the direction of the
做出的一个决定，就能改变曲线的方向
line,
，
right?
对吧？这让
to me that in fact the the most
我更加确信，实际上最
important things and and the biggest
重要的事情和最大的
opportunity is the smallest things
机会往往是那些其他人根本不在乎的微不足道的小事
about.
。
Yes. they'll be thinking about let's get
没错，他们会想着如何邀请
a bigger guest or like you know let's
重量级嘉宾，或者如何搞定那些
get you know the big stuff but it's the
大事，但
small stuff where we have our
我们的
opportunity.
机会却往往藏在这些小事里。
Yes.
是的。
Um so you've identified something that I
所以你指出了我
hold very true and I consider to be my
非常认同的一点，我把它视为我的
professional religion.
职业信条。非常
Um and I appreciate the compliment means
感谢你的赞扬，这对我意义
a lot.
重大。
No no definitely and and and you just I
不不不，你刚刚也
think destroyed a myth that exists as
打破了一个存在的迷思，
well and that is that we should be
那就是我们应该为
sweating the small stuff.
小事烦恼。是的，
Yeah 100%.
百分之百。
Yeah. You know the whole oh don't sweat
你知道那种“别为
no sweat the small stuff because that's
小事烦恼”的说法，因为…… 这就是
where greatest change comes.
最大改变发生的地方。
The same thing with your romantic
恋爱
relationships. People don't sweat the
关系也是如此。人们不会在意那些
small. No
小事。比如，
that one miss hug. You know that one
错过一个拥抱，错过一句“
missed I love you.
我爱你”。
Let's correct it now.
现在就弥补吧。
Correct it now.
现在就弥补。
Yeah.
是的。
So so so powerful. I we have a closing
这太有力量了。我们这个播客有个结尾的
tradition on this podcast where the last
传统，上一位
guest leaves a question for the next
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留一个问题
guest. They don't know who they're
。他们不知道问题会
leaving it for.
留给谁。
Okay. Okay.
好的。好的。
So it's kind of a through line. all the
这就像一条贯穿始终的线索，所有
guests having a conversation with each
嘉宾都在互相交流
other. Um, and I don't get to read the
。嗯，我直到
question until I open the book. Um,
打开书才能看到问题。嗯，
when was the last time you cried of
你上次
happiness?
喜极而泣是什么时候？
Oh my gosh. Cried of happiness?
我的天哪。喜极而泣？我的
Oh my gosh. I know. I mean, I've cried
天哪。我知道。我是说，我
tears of sadness recently. Um,
最近也哭过。嗯，
you've cried tears of sadness recently.
你最近也哭过。是
Yeah, man. I mean, uh, my sister-in-law
啊，老兄。我是说，呃，我嫂子
passed away two weeks ago.
两周前去世了。
My I've I've had I mean, I've had a
我，我是说，我
string of passings in my family that is
家最近接连有人去世，真是令人
devastating. Devastating. First funeral
心碎。 真是令人心碎。这是我第一次
I had to plan, you know, my wife and I
筹办葬礼，你知道，我和妻子一起
planned uh just I mean just Yeah. One of
筹办的，呃，我的意思是，是的。就是那种葬礼
those. So, so you know, I think I think
。所以，你知道，我想到的是
of tears of sadness.
悲伤的泪水。
What did that teach you about life?
这件事教会了你什么人生道理？
Oh, this
哦，这是
someone young and
一个年轻人的故事，很
it's short goes like this. I've I've uh
简短，是这样的。我，呃，
I've been at two death beds.
我曾两次守在病榻前。
One of someone what who I would call
一个是我认为
incredibly young and another one someone
非常年轻的人，另一个
who's lived a full life. They both said
是活得充实的人。他们都说了
the same thing and it haunts me. They
同样的话，这句话一直萦绕在我心头。他们都说：
both said, "This thing goes by quick.
“人生苦短。”
Life goes by quick.
人生苦短，及时行乐。
That's all we get." And it gives me
这就是我们所能得到的全部。”
chills because I think about them
想到他们
looking at me. And that's part of why I
看着我的眼神，我就不寒而栗。这也是为什么我
think I have lived the life or live life
认为我一直以来都这样生活，或者说这样生活，为什么
the way I live it and why I focus so
我如此专注于
much in the moment and why I try to
当下，为什么我努力在
moment because we may never get the
当下表达我对人们的感受，因为我们可能再也遇不到这样的
moment again, you know. Um, so so yeah,
时刻了。嗯，所以，是的，这件事
it's it's taught me a lot. I mean to
教会了我很多。我的意思是，要
to have to write a eulogy you know for
为
someone so young it it it did I will say
一个如此年轻的人写悼词，这确实让我受益匪浅。不过，我也想说
some practical things though it taught
一些实际的事情，它
me it it it taught me we all need wills
教会了我，我们都需要遗嘱，
we all need a will I think that we all
我们都需要一份遗嘱。我认为我们都
should be consciously aware of how we
应该清楚地知道自己
want to be laid to rest
希望如何安葬，
it's a major debate that happens in the
这在家庭中是一个重要的争论点，
family and you know to have that
你知道，
consciously thought out so that we so
认真思考这个问题，这样
that people can your loved ones can
你的亲人才能以
honor you in the way that you want to be
你希望的方式纪念你，
honored I think is incredibly important.
我认为这非常重要。
Um so to have a will and to have
嗯，所以，立一份遗嘱，并事先
pre-thought some of this it's it's not
考虑好这些事情，这并非易事。
morbid. I think we have to understand
有点病态。我觉得我们必须明白，
this is part of our humanity is that we
这是我们人性的一部分，我们
will not be here you know forever. So
终将离世。所以
those are thoughts that are practical
这些都是我认真考虑过的实际问题，
thoughts that I've taken and now I have
现在我已经立好了
a will. Now I've written, you know, how
遗嘱。我已经写好了，比如
where I want to be buried, how I want to
我想葬在哪里，怎么
be buried. These are incredibly
葬。这些都非常
important. Um,
重要。嗯，
I cried like I cried for it could be 30,
我在婚礼上哭了，哭了大概
40 minutes straight at my wedding.
30、40分钟。
[laughter]
[笑声]
I I just cried. I cried the entire
我哭了。我整个
wedding. I just cried and cried and
婚礼都在哭。我一直在哭，哭，
cried and cried. all the pictures of me
哭，哭。所有我哭的照片都是我
crying. Right. [laughter] So, uh those
哭的。对。[笑声] 所以，嗯，这些
are those probably that's the last tears
可能是我最后
of tears of happiness, but I'm I'm
幸福的泪水了，但我真的
incredibly happy. But more than that,
非常幸福。更重要的是，
I'm appreciative, you know, I'm
我很感激，我很
appreciative of life. And it's actually
感激生命。实际上，正是
the tears of sadness that's allowed me
悲伤的泪水让我学会了
to be appreciative.
感激。
Well, Paul, thank you. Um, my team met
保罗，谢谢你。嗯，我的团队
you a couple of weeks ago and they are
几周前见过你，他们非常
obsessed with you and it's and it's
着迷于…… 你，这很
funny because it's not necessarily it's
有趣，因为这不一定是
because of who you were as a person to
因为你对
all of them, how you treated them, how
他们的为人，你对待他们的方式，
wonderful you are, how you know it's all
你有多么出色，你知道这一切都是一些小事
the small stuff. It's kind of the stuff
。就像
you said at the start about that
你一开始说的，关于帮助
underdog and reaching out to the person
弱者，帮助那些
that might be stood up against the wall.
被逼到绝境的人。
It's all of that stuff where everyone in
所有这些都与你当时不在场时所做的事情有关。
was out of the country if I remember
如果我没记错的话，我当时在国外
correctly. But when you came to this
。但当你来到这
building, they were just you converted
栋楼时，他们就都变成了你的
them into raving fans. And I don't know
铁杆粉丝。我不知道
how long you were here or how much you
你在这里待了多久，也不知道你
paid them, but [laughter] I paid them a
付给他们多少钱，但（笑）我付了他们
lot. Okay, that explains it. They were
很多。好吧，这就解释了。他们都成了
just all absolute super fans of yours.
你的超级粉丝。
And your whole philosophy, you said
还有你的理念，
You said something to someone. I'm not
你跟某人说过一些话。我不太
entirely sure who it was, you know,
确定是谁，
because we'd asked we'd essentially
因为我们邀请
asked you to come and help us with
你来帮我们做个
something with a project we're working
项目
on, which I'm very excited about. Um and
，我对此非常兴奋。 嗯，
you said something almost about like
你刚才提到了类似
karma where you you do you do things for
因果报应的东西，你为
people because you kind of believe in
别人做事，是因为你相信
planting that seed like you don't know
播下这颗种子，你不知道
when it will
它什么时候会
it will flourish or when it will you
发芽，什么时候会结出果实，
come to fruition but you just do good
但你只是带着这种因果报应的信念去做善事
Yes. and
。是的，这是一种非常
such an important way to live. And you
重要的生活方式。你
actually helped me to realize that
确实帮助我意识到了这一点，
because the impact you had on all these
因为你对
people here, you turned all of them into
在场的所有人产生了巨大的影响，你把他们都变成了你的
disciples and they're like fairly
门徒，而且他们都是相当
influential people that that you know
有影响力的人，你知道，
they're wellconed. We've got a lot of
他们都很优秀。我们这里有很多
interesting people coming here, you
有趣的人，
know, several days a week. Amazing. And
每周好几天都来。太棒了。
then today, having had a chance to sit
今天，有机会和
with you and ask you some questions that
你坐下来，问你一些问题，这些
really a lot of the questions I ask for
问题其实很多都是我出于
my own selfish pursuit of trying to
私心，想
figure [__] out, you've you've you've
弄明白一些事情而问的，你
changed a lot in me and you're going to
改变了我很多，你也会
change a lot in my relationships. I'm
改变我的很多人际关系。我
partly sat here, you know, winding this
坐在这里，一部分原因是在结束这个
podcast up so I can go fix some [__]
播客，这样我就可以去处理一些事情了。
[laughter]
[笑声]
And I think a lot of people that have
我想很多人都会……
listened to this conversation will be
听过这段对话的人都会有
feeling the same way. Tremendous value,
同样的感受。你真是个极具价值、
tremendously kind man. Um, even when the
非常善良的人。嗯，即使
cameras are off, you're just a class
镜头关掉，你依然风度翩翩，堪称典范
class act. Um, and I have no doubt that
。嗯，我毫不怀疑
you're going to get everything you
你会得到你
deserve that we talked about that sort
应得的一切，就像我们之前讨论过的那些
of like longtail lagging in value.
价值滞后的长尾产品一样。
You're it's going to be your future is
你的未来将会无比
going to be immense. [clears throat]
辉煌。[清嗓子]
Yeah, I I'm I'm honored. I'm
是的，我感到荣幸，我非常感激。
appreciative. I love you.
我爱你。
I love [clears throat] your team, right?
我爱[清嗓子]你的团队，对吧？
I really do. Uh, and I'm It's an honor
我真的爱他们。嗯，我很荣幸能来到
to to be here. So, thank you so much for
这里。所以，非常感谢你们
having me.
邀请我。
I and all of my team love you, too. I
我和我的团队也都非常爱你。我
can speak on behalf of all of them.
可以代表他们所有人说：
Thank you, Paul.
谢谢你，保罗。
Thank you. Thank you. [music]
谢谢你。谢谢。[音乐] 还有一个小插曲
Quick one. We have a brand new sponsor
。我们这个播客迎来了一位全新的赞助商
on this podcast, which I'm very excited
，我非常激动地
to tell you about. They're a brand
要告诉大家。他们是
called Blue Jeans by Verizon, and they
Verizon旗下的Blue Jeans品牌，他们
are a video conferencing and
是一家视频公司。 这款会议
collaboration tool that has changed the
协作工具彻底改变了
game for our team. As someone who's on
我们团队的工作方式。我
calls pretty much 80% of the day,
每天几乎 80% 的时间都在打电话，
building my businesses and speaking to
拓展业务，与
my teams all over the world. It's the
世界各地的团队沟通。Blue
Blue Jeans from all of the other options
Jeans 最突出的优势在于其安全保障，这使其在众多
that are out there in terms of video
视频
conferencing. Their enterprisegrade
会议工具中脱颖而出。其企业级
security means you can protect your
安全功能意味着您可以保护您的
organization from malicious attacks and
组织免受恶意攻击，并
establish real trust with everyone that
与所有参会人员建立真正的信任
joins your meeting. And that is
。Blue Jeans 的
something there are so many things that
诸多优点使其比
better option than the sort of
同类
competitors out there. And I'll be
竞争对手更胜一筹。
use Blue Jeans in the coming episodes.
在接下来的几期节目中，我将详细介绍 Blue Jeans 的方方面面、功能特性以及我使用它的原因。
If you want to check it out, you can
如果您想了解更多信息，可以
head to www.blans.com
访问 www.blans.com
to learn more. [music]
。[音乐]
[music]
[音乐]
Hey.
嘿。
[singing]
[唱歌]
[music]
[音乐]